<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Legis fluvius or, The fountain of the law opened. Shewing the manner method, and forms of proceedings, and pleas on all actions and informations, grounded on all the new and old penal statutes; and the statute it self quoted, upon which every action depends. With presidents for the most usual indictmens : [sic] applicable to all courts of record. Being useful for all atturneys, clerks, and informers. / By A.G.</title>
            <author>A. G.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1657</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 160 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 76 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2014-11">2014-11 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A85701</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing G2</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Thomason E1647_1</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R209091</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99867993</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">99867993</idno>
            <idno type="VID">170677</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A85701)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 170677)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Thomason Tracts ; 207:E1647[1] or 255:E1647[1])</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>Legis fluvius or, The fountain of the law opened. Shewing the manner method, and forms of proceedings, and pleas on all actions and informations, grounded on all the new and old penal statutes; and the statute it self quoted, upon which every action depends. With presidents for the most usual indictmens : [sic] applicable to all courts of record. Being useful for all atturneys, clerks, and informers. / By A.G.</title>
                  <author>A. G.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>[6], 137 [i.e., 141], [1] p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed by J.C. for the said T. Rooks, and are to be sold at the place aforesaid,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London, :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1658 [i.e. 1657]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Advertisement on title page: The best writing-ink for deeds and records, is made and sold by Tho. Rooks, at the east-end of Pauls Church, at the sign of the Lambe, neer the school.</note>
                  <note>Verso of final leaf = advertisement.</note>
                  <note>Numerous errors in pagination.</note>
                  <note>Annotation on Thomason copy: "8ber [i.e. October] 30"; the 8 in the imprint date has been crossed out and replaced with a "7".</note>
                  <note>Reproductions of the original in the British Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Law --  England --  Digests --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2013-02</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-02</date>
            <label>Apex CoVantage</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-04</date>
            <label>Susie Lorand</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-04</date>
            <label>Susie Lorand</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-03</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:170677:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <p> 
               <hi>Legis Fluvius:</hi> OR, The FOUNTAIN Of the LAW OPENED.</p>
            <p>Shewing the Manner Method, and Forms of Proceedings, and Pleas on all Acti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons and Informations, grounded on all the new and old Penal Statutes; and the Statute it ſelf quoted, upon which every Action depends.</p>
            <p>With Preſidents for the moſt uſual In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dictmens: Applicable to all Courts of Record.</p>
            <p>Being uſeful for all Atturneys, Clerks, and INFORMERS.</p>
            <p>By <hi>A. G.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>THe beſt writing-Ink for Deeds and Records, is made and ſold by <hi>Tho. Rooks, at the Eaſt-end of <hi>Pauls</hi> Church, at the Sign of the Lambe, neer the School.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>London,</hi> printed by <hi>J. C.</hi> for the ſaid <hi>T. Rooks,</hi> and are to be ſold at the place aforeſaid. 1658.</p>
            <pb facs="tcp:170677:2"/>
         </div>
         <div type="to_the_reader">
            <pb facs="tcp:170677:2"/>
            <head>To the Reader.</head>
            <p>IT is not to be ſuppoſed, That ever Parliaments would ſpend ſo many long and ſerious Hours in the making Laws, and not in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tend, that they ſhould be put in Execution; yet none are looked upon for more de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſpicable Creatures, then the Proſecutors of the Penal Laws; eſpecially
<pb facs="tcp:170677:3"/> amongſt the Ale-houſes and Gaming-houſes, which are Joynt-tenants, and dwell continually under one Roof: but the High-way-Thief is by far the hone<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſter Man, then the Game<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſter; for
<q>
                  <lg>
                     <l>By him whole Lordſhips have been ſwept away,</l>
                     <l>Credit, &amp; clothes, and all, for one nights play.</l>
                  </lg>
               </q>
            </p>
            <p>But ſince the Law hath
<pb facs="tcp:170677:3"/> ſufficiently provided a Remedy to ſuppreſs theſe Monſters, I doubt not but there will be ingenious Perſons to proſecute them. And becauſe theſe most uſeful Statutes ſeemed to lie obſcure in a voluminous Bulk, and no Preſidents upon them are publickly extant; for the ready eaſe both of the <hi>Informer</hi> and his Clerk, I have ſet down each Penal Statute in brief, and a particular
<pb facs="tcp:170677:4"/> Form of proceeding there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>upon: ſo that if this be duly obſerved and pra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ctiſed, I hope the Cater<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pillers and Locuſts of this Commonwealth, as Fore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtallers, Regradors, In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>groſſers, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> will be ſha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ken off from our Fruit-Trees; for which purpoſe this was compoſed; and hoping it will prove effectu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>al, I conclude.</p>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb facs="tcp:170677:4"/>
            <head>Legis Fluvius, <hi>Or the FOUNTAIN of the LAVV Opened.</hi>
            </head>
            <p>
               <seg rend="decorInit">A</seg> Body without a Spirit is dead, and no more then an Image; of no other uſe are the many wholeſome Laws and Statutes, by great Councils, upon ſeri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ous debate Inſtituted for the preſerva<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion and welfare of this Nation, if life be not given unto them, by putting them in Execution. But indeed they be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing in great Volumes, are not, as they ought to be, known by every one; and to whom they are known, are not Pra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ctiſed by, for want of preſident, or a
<pb n="2" facs="tcp:170677:5"/> Path to walk by: Therefore I'll briefly lay down Platforms of all Sorts for Ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ample, and direct you to the Statute it ſelf for Encouragement.</p>
            <div type="statute">
               <head>Wine without Licenſe.</head>
               <epigraph>
                  <bibl>Statute 7. <hi>E.</hi> 6. 5.</bibl>
                  <q>None ſhall ſell or utter any Wines by retail, &amp;c. without Licenſe, on pain of ten pounds for every offence, &amp;c.</q>
               </epigraph>
               <div type="precedent">
                  <head>The Preſident of an Information a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gainst ſuch as ſell wine with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>out Licenſe.</head>
                  <p>L. M. BE it remembred that H. M. who as well for the Lord Protector of the Common wealth of <hi>England, Scot<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>land,</hi> and <hi>Ireland, &amp;c.</hi> as for himſelf in this behalf, proſecutes; came here into Court the 17 day of <hi>June</hi> in the year of our Lord, 1657. in his own perſon, and aſwel for the ſaid Lord Protector as for himſelf, gave the Court here to under<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtand and be informed, that one I. F. late
<pb n="3" facs="tcp:170677:5"/> of, &amp;c Victualer, at ſixty ſeveral times or turns between the firſt day of <hi>Aug.</hi> laſt paſt, and the day of the Exhibiting this Information, at, &amp;c. in the ſaid County did ſell and utter by Retail to one certain perſon, or to divers certain perſons, whoſe name<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap> to the ſaid H. M. who, &amp;c. as yet are unknown, twenty ſeveral Pints of Claret-wine, wenty ſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>veral Pints of White-wine, and twenty ſeveral Pints of Sack; that is to ſay, one Pinte at every ſeveral time of the afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid ſixty ſeveral times, or turns, within the time aforeſaid, to be drank and ſpent within the Manſion houſe, of him the ſaid I. F. ſituate in, &amp;c. And the ſaid ſixty ſeveral Pints of the ſaid ſeveral Wines aforeſaid, at the aforeſaid ſeveral times or turns, within the time afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid, in the aforeſaid Manſion houſe of the aforeſaid I. F. were drank and ſpent by the aforeſaid I, on certain perſon, or ſeveral certain perſons, to the ſaid H. who, &amp;c. unknown, contrary to the form of the Statute in this caſe made and pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vided: Whereby the ſaid I, hath for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>feited ſix hundred pounds of Lawful money of <hi>England,</hi> That is to ſay, for e<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>very
<pb n="4" facs="tcp:170677:6"/> offence of the aforeſaid ſixty ſever<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>al offences, ſo by him committed in manner and form aforeſaid, and againſt the form of the Statute aforeſaid, ten pounds, in the whole amounting after that rate to the ſaid ſix hundred pounds. Whereupon the ſaid H. aſwel for the ſaid Lord Protector as for himſelf, prays the advice of the Court here in the pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſes, and that he the ſaid H. may have the moyety of the forfeitures aforeſaid, according to the form of the Statute a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>foreſaid. And alſo that he the ſaid I. may come here into Court to anſwer the premiſes, &amp;c. pledges, &amp;c.</p>
               </div>
            </div>
            <div type="statute">
               <head>Plays and Games.</head>
               <epigraph>
                  <bibl>Stat. 33. <hi>H.</hi> 8. 9.</bibl>
                  <q>No perſon or perſons ſhall keep, hold, or maintain, either in his or their dwell<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing or manſion Houſe, Yard, or Back<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſide, or any place, any unlawful Games; or ſhall ſuffer any perſons to play at Ta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bles Cards, or Dice, Tennis, Coyts, Claſh, Logga<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>s, or any other unlawful Game, on pain of forty ſhillings a day
<pb n="5" facs="tcp:170677:6"/> for every ſuch offence: one moyety to the Protector, the other moyety to any per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon that will ſue for the ſame in any Court of Record, &amp;c.</q>
               </epigraph>
               <div type="precedent">
                  <head>An Information againſt a Gaming-houſe.</head>
                  <p>L. M. BE it remembred, that I. S. who aſwel for the Lord Protector of the Commonwealth, &amp;c. as for him<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelf in this behalf, proſecutes; came here into Court the twelfth day of <hi>February,</hi> in the year of our Lord, 1656. in his own perſon, and aſwel for the ſaid Lord Protector as for himſelf, gave the Court here to underſtand and be informed, that one G. S. late of <hi>London,</hi> Victualler, the 24 day of <hi>June</hi> laſt paſt, and conti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nually afterwards by the ſpace of twen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty days, for the lucre and gain of the ſaid G. S. by himſelf and his ſervants at L. aforeſaid, That is to ſay, in the Pariſh of bleſſed <hi>Mary Bow,</hi> and Ward of Cheap, did keep, hold, and maintain a common gaming-houſe, of, and for Tables, Cards and Dice, Coyts, Claſh, Tennis, Loggats, Bowls, and Nine-pins; and of and for
<pb n="6" facs="tcp:170677:7"/> another unlawful game, called Shove<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>groat, otherwiſe Slidethrift: and at the ſame unlawful games, every day by all the time aforeſaid, at L. aforeſaid, at his dwelling houſe aforeſaid, divers perſons, ſubjects of this Commonwealth, to play, did permit and ſuffer, againſt the form of the Statute in this caſe made and provided. By means whereof he, the ſaid G. hath forfeited to the ſaid Lord Protector and the ſaid I. S. who, &amp;c. the ſum of forty pounds of lawful money of <hi>England:</hi> to wit, for every day of the ſaid twenty ſeveral days, wherein he kept the ſaid gaming-houſe as aforeſaid, the ſum of forty ſhillings; in the whole, a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mounting after that rate to the ſaid for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty pounds: Whereupon the ſaid I. S. aſwel for the ſaid Lord Protector, as for himſ<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>lf, prayeth the advice of the Court here in the premiſes, and that he the ſaid I. S. may have one moyety of the ſaid forfei<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>ures, according to the form of the Statu<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>e aforeſaid, and that he the ſaid G. S. may come here into Court to anſwer the prem<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="2 letters">
                        <desc>••</desc>
                     </gap>e<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>, &amp;c.</p>
                  <p>By the ſame Statute, every perſon u<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſing
<pb n="7" facs="tcp:170677:7"/> or haunting any ſuch gaming-houſe, ſhall forfeit 6s. 8d. for every day he ſhall uſe the ſame: and every Artificer, Journey-man, or Water-man, &amp;c. 2 s. Theſe forfeitures to be divided <hi>ut ſu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pra.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
            </div>
            <div type="statute">
               <head>Recuſants.</head>
               <epigraph>
                  <bibl>Stat. 23. <hi>Eliz.</hi> 1.</bibl>
                  <q>Every perſon of the Age of ſixteen years and upwards, ſhall every Lords day du<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly repair to their Pariſh Church, or ſome other Pariſh Church, on pain to forfeit for every moneth they ſhall make default, twenty pounds, to be divided in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>to three equal parts<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> one part to the Protector, the other part to the poor of the Pariſh, where the defendant dwells, and another part to the Informer, &amp;c.</q>
               </epigraph>
               <div type="precedent">
                  <head>Information againſt Recuſants.</head>
                  <p>BE it remembred that W. S. who as well for the now Lord Protector and the poor of the Pariſh of S. in the ſaid County, as for himſelf in this be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>half,
<pb n="8" facs="tcp:170677:8"/> proſecures; came here into Court the fifteenth day of <hi>April,</hi> in the year of our Lord, 1657. in his own perſon, and gave the Court here to underſtand and be Informed, That one P. S. late of the Pariſh of S. in the ſaid County of G. who the twenty ninth day of <hi>September,</hi> in the year of our Lord, 1656. was of the Age of ſixteen years and more, and abiding and inhabiting within the Common<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wealth of <hi>England,</hi> that is to ſay, in the Pariſh of S. in the County aforeſaid, and from the aforeſaid twenty ninth day of <hi>September,</hi> in the year aforeſaid unto the day of the Exhibiting this informa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion, That is to ſay, by the ſpace of ſix whole moneths, or more, did not re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pair nor m<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>ke his endeavour to repair un<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>o the Pariſh Church of S. aforeſaid, nor unto any other lawful or publike Church or Chappel, for the hearing of Divine Service, and Sermons, according to the Laws and Ordinances of the Church and Commonwealth of <hi>Eng<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>land,</hi> for the publike Worſhip and Ser<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vice of God, made, and ordained; and there remain orderly, and nor go away, during the time of publike Prayer and
<pb n="9" facs="tcp:170677:8"/> Preaching, or other Doctrine and Ser<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vices, according to the Ordinances of the Commonwealth of <hi>England,</hi> for the publike Service and Divine Worſhip of God, made and ordained, and there uſed and adminiſtred. But for the whole time aforeſaid, at the Pariſh aforeſaid, in the County aforeſaid, having no lawful excuſe, did voluntarily and obſtinately forbear the ſame, againſt the form of the Statute in this Caſe made and provided. Whereupon the ſaid W. S. aſwel for the ſaid Lord Protector, and the poor of the ſaid Pariſh, as for himſelf, prays the ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vice of the Court here in the premiſes, And that due proces of Law may be a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>warded againſt the ſaid P. S. in this be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>half, And that the ſaid P. S. may there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>of be lawfully convicted, and for his offence aforeſaid, may forf<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>it 120l. of lawful money of <hi>England,</hi> to wit, 20 l. for each moneth of the ſaid ſix whole mone<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>hs, in which the aforeſaid P. S. did not repair to the Church as afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid; And that the ſaid forfei<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>ure may be divided into three equal parts, And that the aforeſaid W. S. may have there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>of his third part, according to the form
<pb n="10" facs="tcp:170677:9"/> of the Statute aforeſaid: And moreover, That the aforeſaid P. S. may come here into Court to anſwer the premiſes, &amp;c.</p>
               </div>
            </div>
            <div type="statute">
               <head>Shooemakers.</head>
               <epigraph>
                  <bibl>Stat. 1. <hi>Jam.</hi> 22.</bibl>
                  <q>
                     <hi>Shoomakers ſhall make their Shooes and Boots, &amp;c. of good and ſufficient Stuff; and ſowe them well, in pain to forfeit for every default or offence</hi> 3s. 4d. <hi>beſides the full value of the Wares otherwiſe made or ſold, &amp;c.</hi>
                  </q>
               </epigraph>
               <p>It were good if this were well look<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed after; for it is a common practice now among Shoomakers to make the Rands of Shooes with Calves-leather; ſo that aſſoon as it comes to the wet, the ſole rends from the upper Leather, and can never be mended. And to make the Heels of unlawful Leather is uſual. At this time I have a pair of Shooes on my feet, ſold to me for Neats-leather in Saint <hi>Martins-lane;</hi> and the pieces of the heels are Horſe-hide, as thoſe that deal in Leather inform me: indeed if
<pb n="11" facs="tcp:170677:9"/> they did not look like Leather, I ſhould have imagined they had been Paper.</p>
               <div type="precedent">
                  <head>Information.</head>
                  <p>BE it remembred that <hi>John Saubrigde,</hi> who as well for the Lord Protector or <hi>England, Scotland,</hi> and <hi>Ireland &amp;c.</hi> as for himſelf in this behalf, proſecutes; came here into Court the fifteenth day of <hi>June,</hi> in the year of our Lord, &amp;c. and gave the Court here to under<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>tand, and be informed, that one N. T. late of L. Cordwainer, between the fir<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>t day of <hi>Ja<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nuary</hi> laſt paſt, and the day of the Exhi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>biting this Information at <hi>London</hi> afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid, to wit, in the Pariſh of, &amp;<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>. and Ward, &amp;c. at twenty ſeveral times or turns within the time aforeſaid, did ſell and utter to divers and ſeveral perſons, whoſe names to the ſaid I. S. who, &amp;c. as yet are unknown, twenty pair of Boots, price of every pair thereof ten ſhillings; twenty pair of Shooes, price of every pair thereof three ſhillings four pence. And the ſaid I. S. as well for the ſaid Lord Protector, as for himſelf, will verifie, that the ſaid twenty ſeveral
<pb n="12" facs="tcp:170677:10"/> pair of Boots, and the ſaid twenty ſever<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>al pair of Shooes, were not made of good and ſufficient Stuff, but the R<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>nds thereof were made of Calves-leather; And the ſaid Boots and Shooes, were ſowed with unwrought and rotten thread, mixed with Rozen and Brim<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtone, contrary to the form of the Sta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tute in this Caſe made and provided. By means whereof the ſaid N. T. hath forfeited to the ſaid Lord Protector, and the ſaid I. S. who as well, &amp;c. the ſum of thirteen pounds ſix ſhillings and eight pence, of lawful money of <hi>England,</hi> That is to ſay, the value of the ſaid Boots and Shooes, ſo by him of unlawful and un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſufficient Stuff made and ſold, as afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid: And alſo the ſum of three pounds ſix ſhillings and eight pence, That is to ſay, for every offence of the aforeſaid twenty ſeveral offences, the ſum of three ſhillings and four pence, of like lawful money of <hi>England:</hi> which ſaid forfei<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tures do amount in the whole, to the ſum of ſixteen pounds thirteen ſhillings four pence, of lawful money of <hi>England.</hi> Whereupon the ſaid I. S. as well for the ſaid Lord Protector, as for himſelf, pray<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>eth
<pb n="13" facs="tcp:170677:10"/> the advice of the Court here in the premiſes; and that due proces of Law may be awarded againſt him the ſaid N. T. in this behalf, And that he the ſaid I. S. who, &amp;c. may have one moyety of the ſaid forfeitures, according to the form of the Statute aforeſaid, And alſo that he the ſaid N. T. may come here in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>to Court to anſwer the premiſes, &amp;c.</p>
               </div>
            </div>
            <div type="statute">
               <head>Upholſters.</head>
               <epigraph>
                  <bibl>Stat. 9. 11. <hi>H.</hi> 7. 19. 5. 6. <hi>E.</hi> 6. 2. 3.</bibl>
                  <q>
                     <p>
                        <hi>None ſhall make, to the intent to ſell, or offer to be ſold, any Featherbed, Bol<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſter, Pillow, Cuſhion, Quilt, Mat<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>treſs, &amp;c. except ſuch as are ſtuffed with one ſort of ſtuff,</hi> viz. <hi>Clean Wooll, Fea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thers, or Flocks alone, and not mixed with hair, or any unlawful ſtuff, in pain to forfeit the ſame, ſo ſold or put to ſale, or the value thereof.</hi>
                     </p>
                     <p>Which ſaid forfeitures are to be di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vided betwixt the Protector and the pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſecutor.</p>
                  </q>
               </epigraph>
               <div type="precedent">
                  <pb n="14" facs="tcp:170677:11"/>
                  <head>Information againſt Upholſters.</head>
                  <p>BE it remembred, that I. S. who as well for the now Lord Protector, as for himſelf in this behalf, proſecutes; came here into Court the fifteenth day of <hi>June,</hi> in the year of Lord, 1657. in his own perſon, and gave the Court here to underſtand, and be informed, that one J. J. late of <hi>London</hi> Upholſter, be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tween the twenty fourth day of <hi>June</hi> laſt paſt, and the day of the Exhibiting this information at <hi>London,</hi> aforeſaid, That is to ſay, in the Pariſh of bleſſed <hi>Mary Bow,</hi> and Ward of Cheap, uſing and ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>erciſing the Art, Trade, and Myſtery of an Upholſter, did ſell and utter to divers perſons, whoſe names to the ſaid I. S. who, &amp;c. as yet are unknown, twenty Beds, price of every Bed forty ſhillings; twenty Pillows, price of every Pillow ten ſhillings; twenty Bolſters, price of every Bolſter twenty ſhillings; twenty dozen of Cuſhions, price of every dozen thereof forty ſhillings; twenty dozen of low Stools, price of every dozen thereof three pounds; ten dozen of
<pb n="15" facs="tcp:170677:11"/> high Chairs, price of every dozen there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>of four pounds. And the ſaid I. S. as well for the ſaid Lord Protector, as for himſelf, will verifie that the ſaid Beds, Pillows, Bolſters, Cuſhions, Stools, and Chairs, were ſtuffed with mixed and unlawful ſtuff, as hair and feathers mixed together; and not with clean fea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thers, or clean flocks alone; againſt the form of the Statute in this Caſe made and provided: By means whereof, he the ſaid J. J. hath forfeited to the ſaid Lord Protector and the ſaid I. S. who as well, &amp;c. the ſum of two hundred and ten pounds of lawful money of <hi>England:</hi> That is to ſay, the value of the ſaid goods and wares, ſo by him in manner and form aforeſaid, and againſt the form of the Statute aforeſaid, of unlawful and mixed ſtuff, ſold and put to ſale afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid. Whereupon the ſaid I. S. as well for the ſaid Lord Protector, as for him<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelf, prayeth the advice of the Court here in the premiſes. And that due proceſs, &amp;c. And that he, the ſaid I. S. who, &amp;c. may have one moyety of the ſaid forfeitures, according the form of the Statute aforeſaid: And moreover,
<pb n="16" facs="tcp:170677:12"/> that he the ſaid J. J<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> may come here in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>to Court, to anſwer the premiſes, &amp;c.</p>
               </div>
            </div>
            <div type="statutes">
               <head>Foreſtalling.</head>
               <epigraph>
                  <bibl>Stat. 5. 6. <hi>E.</hi> 6. 14.</bibl>
                  <q>If any perſon ſhall buy or contract for any Merchandize, V<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>ctual, or other thing whatſoever, in the way before it be brought unto any F<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>i<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap> or Market, where it ſhould be ſold; or ſhall c<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>uſe the ſame to be ſo brought, or ſhall diſſwade people from bringing any ſuch Commo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dity unto ſuch place; or being brought ſhall perſwade them to inhance the price thereof, every ſuch perſon and perſons, ſhall be adjudged a foreſtaller.</q>
                  <bibl>Stat 1 <hi>Edw.</hi>
                  </bibl>
                  <q>He ſhall be adjudged a Regrador, that buys any Grain, Wine, Fiſh, Butter, Cheeſe, Candles, Tallow, Sheep, L<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>mbs, Calves, Swine, Piggs, Geeſe, Capons, Hens, Chickens, Pigeons, Coneys, or any other dead Victuals whatſoever, brought to a Fair or Mar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ket to be ſold there, and doth ſell the ſame
<pb n="17" facs="tcp:170677:12"/> again within the ſame Fair or Market, or in any other Fair or Market, within four miles.</q>
                  <bibl>Stat. idem.</bibl>
                  <q>He is an ingroſſer who ſhall get into his hands, by buying, contract, or promiſe (other then by demiſe) any corn grow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing on the ground, or other Grain, But<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter, Cheeſe, Fiſh, or other dead Victuals whatſoever, with an intent to fell it again.</q>
               </epigraph>
               <div type="precedent">
                  <head>Information againſt an Ingroſſer for buying Corn on the ground.</head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Eſſex</hi> ſſ. BE it remembred, that I. S. who as well for the L. Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tector of <hi>England, Scotland,</hi> and <hi>Ireland,</hi> and the Dominions thereunto belong<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing as for himſelf in this behalf, proſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cutes; came here into Court the ſeven<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>teenth day of <hi>June,</hi> in the year of our Lord, 1657. in his own perſon, and gave the Court here to underſtand, and be informed, that one R. D. late of D. in the County aforeſaid<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> Chandler, be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tween the firſt day of <hi>April</hi> laſt paſt, and
<pb n="18" facs="tcp:170677:13"/> the day of the Exhibiting this Informa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion, at E. in the ſaid County, did in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>groſs and obtain into his hands and poſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſeſsion, by buying, and not by demiſe, grant, ſale of Land or Tythes, of divers perſons, whoſe names to the ſaid I. S. who, &amp;c. as yet are unknown; ten Acres of Wheat, every Acre thereof of the va<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lue of ſix pounds; forty Acres of Rye, every Acre of the value of four pounds; an hundred Acres of Barley, every Acre of the value of three pounds, being and growing in the blades, and ſtanding Corn, in the fields of D. aforeſaid in the ſaid County, with an intent to ſell again the Grain coming thereof, and of every parcel thereof, after the buying thereof; contrary to the form of the Statute in this Caſe made and provided. Whereby the ſaid R. for this firſt offence hath for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>feited five hundred and twenty pounds, of lawful money of <hi>England,</hi> to wit, the value of the Corn aforeſaid, ſo by him in manner and form aforeſaid, and againſt the form of the Statute aforeſaid, bought and ingroſſed. Whereupon the ſaid R. B. who as well, &amp;c. prayeth the advice of the Court here in the pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſes,
<pb n="19" facs="tcp:170677:13"/> and that he the ſaid R. B. who, &amp;c. may have the moyety of the forfei<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tures aforeſaid, according to the form of the Statute aforeſaid. And that the ſaid R. D may be accounted an unlaw<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ful ingroſſer, and may ſuffer impriſon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment of his body by the ſpace of two moneths, without bayl or mainprize, and alſo that the ſaid R. D. may come here into Court to anſwer the premiſes, &amp;c.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="penalty">
                  <head>The penalty againſt Foreſtallers, Regra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dors, and Ingroſſors.</head>
                  <p>The firſt offence is forfeiture of the goods ſo bought or had, and two moneths impriſonment without bayl; the ſecond offence is double the value, and ſix moneths impriſonment without bayl: The party offending the third time ſhall forfeit all his goods, be ſet upon the Pillory, and impriſoned at the Kings pleaſure.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="precedent">
                  <pb n="20" facs="tcp:170677:14"/>
                  <head>An Information againſt a Foreſtal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ler.</head>
                  <p>L. ſſ. BE it remembred, that I. S. who as well for the Lord Prote<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ctor, &amp;c. as for himſelf in this behalf, proſecutes; came here into Court the thirteenth day of <hi>June,</hi> in the year of our Lord, 1657. in his own perſon, and gave the Court here to underſtand and be informed, that one E. D. late of <hi>Lon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>don,</hi> Chandler, between the firſt day of <hi>January</hi> laſt paſt, and the day of the ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>hibiting this information, at <hi>London</hi> a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>foreſaid; to wit, in the Pariſh of bleſſed <hi>Mary-Bow,</hi> and Ward of Cheap, did by way of foreſtalling and unlawful ingroſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſing, buy of ſeveral perſons, whoſe names to the ſaid I, who as well, &amp;c. as yet are unknown at, divers &amp; ſeveral times two hundred pound weight of Butter, price of every pound thereof ſix pence; two hundred pound weight of Cheeſe, price of every pound thereof, three pence; four hundred Eggs, price of eve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry hundred thereof four ſhillings; two hundred pound weight of Bacon, price
<pb n="21" facs="tcp:170677:14"/> of every pound weight thereof, four pence; ten dozen of Pigeons, price of every dozen thereof, three ſhillings; five dozen of Capons, price of every do<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>zen thereof, one pound four ſhillings; five dozen of Pullets, price of every do<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>zen thereof, eighteen ſhillings; five do<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>zen of Turkeys, price of every dozen, forty ſhillings, contrary to the form of the Statute in this Caſe made and provi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ded: by means whereof, he the ſaid E. D. hath forfeited to the ſaid Lord Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tector, and the ſaid I. S. who, &amp;c. for this his firſt offence, the ſum of thirty and three pounds twelve ſhillings eight pence, That is to ſay, the value of the ſaid goods and victuals, ſo by him, in manner and form aforeſaid, and againſt the form of the Statute aforeſaid, bought and foreſtalled. Whereupon the ſaid I. S. as well for the ſaid Lord Protector, as for himſelf, prayeth the advice of the Court here in the premiſes. And that due proceſs, &amp;c. And that he, the ſaid I. S. who, &amp;c. may have one moy<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ety of the ſaid forfeitures, according to the form of the Statute aforeſaid: And that he the ſaid E. D. may be adjudged
<pb n="22" facs="tcp:170677:15"/> an unlawful foreſtaller, and be thereof convicted, and may alſo for his firſt of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fence ſuffer two moneths impriſonment of his body without bayl, according to the form of the Statute aforeſaid: and moreover, that he come here into Court to anſwer the premiſes, &amp;c.</p>
               </div>
            </div>
            <div type="statute">
               <head>Againſt Artificers uſing a Manual Occupation, not being Apprentice there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>unto.</head>
               <epigraph>
                  <bibl>Stat. 5. <hi>Eliz.</hi> 4.</bibl>
                  <q>None who hath not ſerved as an Ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>prentice ſeven years, to any Art or My<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtery now uſed, ſhall uſe the ſame, or ſet any others to work therein, who hath not ſerved out that time, on pain to for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>feit forty ſhillings for every moneth, to be divided between the Queen and the proſecutor.</q>
               </epigraph>
               <div type="precedent">
                  <pb n="23" facs="tcp:170677:15"/>
                  <head>The Information for uſing a Trade not being an Apprentice.</head>
                  <p>L. ſſ. BE it remembred, that I. S. who as well for the now Lord Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tector, as for himſelf in this behalf, pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſecutes; came here into Court the twenty third day of <hi>January,</hi> in the year of Lord, 1656. in his own perſon, and as well for the ſaid Lord Protector as for himſelf, gave the Court here to un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>derſtand, and be informed, that one L. M. late of <hi>London</hi> Yeoman, the twen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tieth day of <hi>February</hi> laſt paſt, and con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tinually afterwards, until the day of the Exhibiting this information; to wit, by the ſpace of eleven whole moneths and more, at <hi>London</hi> aforeſaid, to wit, in the Pariſh of bleſſed <hi>Mary Bow,</hi> and Ward of Cheap, by himſelf and his ſer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vants, for his proper uſe, did uſe and ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>erciſe, the Art, Science, Myſtery, and Occupation of a Combmaker, being a Science, Artifice, Myſtery, Occupation, and Art, uſed and occupied within this Commonwealth of <hi>England,</hi> the twelfth day of <hi>January,</hi> in the firſt year of the
<pb n="24" facs="tcp:170677:16"/> Reign of our Lady <hi>Elizabeth,</hi> late Queen of <hi>England:</hi> Where in truth the ſaid R. N. the ſaid twelfth day of <hi>January,</hi> in the ſaid fifth year of the Reign of our ſaid Lady Queen <hi>Elizabeth,</hi> late Queen of <hi>England,</hi> &amp;c. did not uſe, exerciſe, nor enjoy the ſaid Science, Art, Myſte<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry, nor Occupation of a Combmaker, nor any other Art, Myſtery, nor Manu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>al Ocbupation, nor was at any time edi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fied in the ſaid Art, Myſtery, or Manu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>al Occupation of a Combmaker, nor of any other Art, Myſtery, or Manual Oc<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cupation, as an Apprentice by the ſpace of ſeven years; Againſt the form of the Statute in the fifth year of our ſaid La<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dy <hi>Elizabeth,</hi> Queen of <hi>England,</hi> &amp;c. in this Caſe made and provided. Whereby the ſaid R. N. hath forfeited to the ſaid Lord Protector, and to the ſaid I. S. who as well, &amp;c. twenty two pounds of good and lawful money of <hi>England,</hi> viz. for every moneth of the ſaid eleven moneths, in which the ſaid R. N. ſo as aforeſaid, the ſaid Science, Art, Myſtery, or Manual Occupation of a Combma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ker, againſt the form of the ſaid Sta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tute, did uſe, occupy, and exerciſe, for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty
<pb n="25" facs="tcp:170677:16"/> ſhillings of lawful money of <hi>England;</hi> in the whole, amounting after that rate to the ſaid two and twenty pounds: Whereupon the ſaid I. S. who as well, &amp;c. prayeth the advice of the Court here in the premiſes, and that due pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceſs of Law may be awarded againſt the ſaid R. N. in this behalf; And that he, the ſaid I. S. who, &amp;c. may have the moyety of the forfeitures aforeſaid, ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cording to the form of the Statute a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>foreſaid; and that he, the ſaid R. N. may come here into Court to anſwer the premiſes, &amp;c.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="precedent">
                  <head>An Information againſt Tallow-Chan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dlers, in the City of <hi>London</hi> onely.</head>
                  <p>L. ſſ. BE it remembred, that A. B. who as well for the now Lord Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tector, as alſo for the Chamberlain of the City of <hi>London</hi> aforeſaid, as for him<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelf in this behalf, proſecutes; came here into Court the twentieth day of <hi>November,</hi> in the year of our Lord, 1656. in his own perſon, and gave the Court here to underſtand, and be infor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>med, that one N. H. late of <hi>London,</hi>
                     <pb n="26" facs="tcp:170677:17"/> Tallow-Chandler, the twentieth day of <hi>December</hi> laſt paſt, and continually af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>terwards, till the day of the Exhibiting this Information, That is to ſay, by the ſpace of ten whole moneths, and more; at <hi>London</hi> aforeſaid, to wit, in the Pa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riſh of bleſſed <hi>Mary Bow,</hi> and Ward of Cheap, within the Liberties and Walls of <hi>London</hi> aforeſaid, did keep, hold, and maintain a common melting houſe for Tallow, And in the ſaid houſe the ſaid twentieth day of <hi>November,</hi> and nine<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>teen other ſeveral days and times with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>in the time aforeſaid, at the City of <hi>Lon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>don</hi> aforeſaid, in the Pariſh and Ward aforeſaid, did melt Tallow, to the great annoyance of the Pariſhioners of the Pariſh aforeſaid, againſt the form of the Statute in this Caſe made and provided, and againſt the Cuſtomes, Liberties, and Priviledges of the City of <hi>London</hi> afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid: Whereupon the ſaid A. as well for the ſaid Lord Protector, as alſo for the Chamberlain of the City of <hi>London</hi> aforeſaid, as for himſelf, prayeth the ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vice of the Court here in the premiſes; And that due proceſs of Law may be a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>warded againſt the ſaid N. H. in this be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>half:
<pb n="27" facs="tcp:170677:17"/> And that the ſaid N. H. may for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>feit five pounds of lawful money of <hi>England,</hi> for every day of the ſaid twen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty ſeveral days, in which the ſaid N. in his houſe aforeſaid, in the form afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid, and againſt the form of the Statute aforeſaid, did melt Tallow aforeſaid, within the Walls and Liberties of the City of <hi>London</hi> aforeſaid; in the whole amounting after that rate to an hundred pounds, of lawful money of <hi>England;</hi> And that the ſaid forfeitures may be di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vided into three equal parts. And that he the ſaid A. may have one third part of the forfeitures aforeſaid, according to the form of the Statute aforeſaid: And that he the ſaid N. H. may come here into Court, to anſwer in and upon the premiſes, &amp;c.</p>
               </div>
            </div>
            <div type="statute">
               <head>Reſidence.</head>
               <epigraph>
                  <bibl>Stat. 21. <hi>H</hi> 8. 13.</bibl>
                  <q>Every Spiritual perſon promoted to any Dignity or Benefice, or being be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neficed with any Perſonage or Vica<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rage, that he be perſonally reſident and
<pb n="28" facs="tcp:170677:18"/> abiding, upon his ſaid Dignity, Pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bendary, Rectory, Benefice, or Vica<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rage, or at one of them at leaſt, in pain to forfeit for not being ſo reſident by the ſpace of a moneth together, the ſum of ten pounds, to be divided betwixt the King and the proſecutor.</q>
               </epigraph>
               <div type="precedent">
                  <head>An Information againſt a Miniſter for non-reſidency.</head>
                  <p>L. ſſ. BE it remembred, that I. S. who as well for the now Lord Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tector as for himſelf in this behalf, pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſecutes; came here into Court the three and twentieth day of <hi>Jan.</hi> this Term in his own perſon, and as well for the ſaid Lord Protector as for himſelf, gave the Court here to underſtand and be infor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>med, that whereas by a certain Act of Parliament of King <hi>Henry</hi> the eighth, held at <hi>Weſtminſter,</hi> in the County of <hi>Middleſex,</hi> the third day of <hi>November,</hi> the one and twentieth year of his Reign, it ſtands enacted by the Authority of the ſame Parliament, That after the Feaſt of Saint <hi>Michael</hi> the Arch-angel, then next following, no perſon Spiritual,
<pb n="29" facs="tcp:170677:18"/> Secular, nor Regular, of whatſoever de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gree he or they were, ſhould from thence take to Farm, to him or to any perſon or perſons to his proper uſe, of the Leafe or Grant of our Lord the King, or of any other perſon or perſons; by Letters Patents, Indenture or Writing, or by Word or otherwiſe, by any means, any Mannors, Lands, or Tenements, or o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther Hereditaments, for term of life, for term of years, or at will, under the pain of forfeiture of ten pounds for every moneth, wherein be, or any o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther to his uſe, did occupy any ſuch Farm; the one moyety of ſuch forfei<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ture to be to our ſaid Lord the King, and the other moyety thereof to be to any ſuch perſon as ſhould proſecute ſuit for the ſame, in any of the Courts of Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cord, of our ſaid Lord the King: In which Action and Suit, no wager of Law was to be admitted for the Defendant. And further it is enacted by the Autho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rity aforeſaid; That all ſuch Demiſes made, or then thereafter to be made, to any ſuch Spiritual perſon or perſons, or to any others to their uſe, for term of life, years, or at will, of any Mannors,
<pb n="30" facs="tcp:170677:19"/> Lands, Tenements, or Hereditaments, of which they or any of them ſhould take any profit, or medling by them<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelves, or by any other to their uſe, af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter the ſame Feaſt of Saint <hi>Michael,</hi> by colour of any Demiſe or Grant, and by them not bargained, granted, and ſold before the ſaid Feaſt, as is before limi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted, ſhould from thence be void and of no ſorce, as well againſt the Leſſor and Leſſors, Grantor and Grantors, their Heirs and Aſſigns, and againſt any of them, as againſt the Leſſee and Leſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſees, And their Executors and Aſſigns, and every of them. And laſtly, it is Enacted by the Authority of the ſame Parliament, that as well every Spiritual Perſon, then promoted to any Arch-deaconry, Deaconry, or Dignity, in any Monaſtery or Cathedral Church, or any Covent or Collegiate Church, or being Beneficed with any Parſonage or Vica<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rage; That all and ſingular Spiritual per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon or perſons, which from thence here<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>after ſhould be promoted unto any Place, Dignities, or Benefices, with any Parſonage or Vicaridge, from the Feaſt of Saint <hi>Michael</hi> the Arch-angel, then
<pb n="31" facs="tcp:170677:19"/> next following; ſhould be perſonally reſident, and abiding at and upon their Dignities, Prebendaries, or Benefices, or at one of them at leaſt. And in caſe any ſuch Spiritual Perſon at any time, af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter the ſame Feaſt, ſhould not keep re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſidency at one of his Dignities, Preben<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>daries, or Benefices aforeſaid, but ſhall abſent himſelf voluntarily, by the ſpace of one moneth at one time, or by the ſpace of two moneths to be numbred at ſeveral times in any one year, And ſhall make his reſidence and habitation in any other place by ſuch time aforeſaid, That then he or they ſhall forfeit for e<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>very ſuch default, ten pounds of lawful money of <hi>England:</hi> Yet nevertheleſs, A. W. lately of <hi>London</hi> aforeſaid, being a Spiritual Perſon, and Rector of the Pa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riſh of Saint <hi>E.</hi> in <hi>London</hi> aforeſaid, very little weighing the Statute aforeſaid, nor in any manner fearing the puniſhment in the ſaid Statute contained, after the publiſhing of the Statute aforeſaid, and before the day of the Exhibiting this in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>formation, to wit, the tenth day of <hi>Fe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bruary</hi> laſt paſt, and continually after<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wards by the ſpace of eleven whole
<pb n="32" facs="tcp:170677:20"/> moneths then next following; did vo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>luntarily abſent himſelf from his Recto<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry aforeſaid: ſo that the aforeſaid A. W. did in no wiſe make his abode or reſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dency in, at, or upon his Rectory afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid, by the time aforeſaid, againſt the form of the Statute in that Caſe made and provided as aforeſaid; By means whereof, the ſaid A. W. hath forfeited to the ſaid Lord Protector, and to the ſaid I. S. who as well, &amp;c, the ſum of an hundred and ten pounds of lawful money of <hi>England,</hi> That is to ſay, for each moneth of the aforeſaid eleven moneths, ten pounds; in the whole, a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mounting after that rate to the ſaid ſum of an hundred and ten pounds: Where<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>upon the ſaid I. S. as well for the ſaid Lord Protector as for himſelf, prayeth the advice of the Court here in the pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſes; And that due proceſs of Law may be awarded againſt him the ſaid A. W. in this behalf; And that he the ſaid I. S. who &amp;c. may have one moyety of the ſaid forfeitures, according to the form of the Statute aforeſaid: And alſo that the ſaid A. W. may come here into Court to anſwer in and upon the pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſes, &amp;c.</p>
               </div>
            </div>
            <div type="statute">
               <pb n="33" facs="tcp:170677:20"/>
               <head>Dyers.</head>
               <epigraph>
                  <bibl>Statute.</bibl>
                  <q>No Dyer ſhall dye any Cloth with Log<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wood, Orchel, or Cork, or other deceit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ful way, or means, on pain to forfeit the ſame or the value thereof.</q>
               </epigraph>
               <div type="precedent">
                  <head>An Information againſt Dyers uſing Logwood.</head>
                  <p>L. ſſ. BE it remembred, that I. B. who as well for the now Lord Protector as for himſelf in this behalf, proſecutes: came here into Court the ſixth day of <hi>June,</hi> in the year of our Lord 1657. in his own perſon, and as well for the ſaid Lord Protector as for him<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelf, gives the Court here to underſtand and be informed, that one D. S. late of <hi>London,</hi> Dyer, between the firſt day of <hi>April</hi> laſt paſt, and the day of the Exhi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>biting this Information at <hi>London,</hi> That is to ſay, in the Pariſh of bleſſed <hi>Mary Bow,</hi> and Ward of Cheap, uſing and ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>erciſing the Art and Myſtery of a Dyer,
<pb n="34" facs="tcp:170677:21"/> did uſe for the dying of broad Woollen-cloathes, Kerſeys and Bays, a certain outlandiſh Wood called Logwood, o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>therwiſe Blockwood, with other deceit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ful means, and within the time afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid, at <hi>London</hi> aforeſaid, in the Pariſh and Ward aforeſaid, he the ſaid D. S. ten broad Woollen-cloathes, price of eve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry Cloth thereof ten pounds; ten Ker<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſeys, price of every Kerſey thereof five pounds; ten pieces of Bays, price of every piece thereof four pounds, with the ſaid Logwood, otherwiſe Block<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wood, and other falſe and deceitful means as aforeſaid, did dye and colour contrary to the form of a certain Sta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tute of the three and twentieth year of the Raign of Qu. <hi>Elizabeth,</hi> late Queen of <hi>England,</hi> &amp;c. in ſuch Caſe made and provided; by means whereof, he the ſaid D. S. hath forfeited to the ſaid Lord Protector, and to the ſaid I. B. who, &amp;c. the ſum of an hundred fourſcore and ten pounds of lawful money of <hi>England,</hi> That is to ſay, the value of the ſaid Woollen-clothes, Kerſeys, and Bays, ſo by him in manner and form aforeſaid, and againſt the form of Statute aforeſaid
<pb n="35" facs="tcp:170677:21"/> with the ſaid Logwood, otherwiſe Blockwood, and other falſe and deceit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ful ways and means dyed and coloured as aforeſaid: Whereupon the ſaid I. B. as well for the ſaid Lord Protector as for himſelf, prayeth the advice of the Court here in the premiſes: And that he, the ſaid I. B. who, &amp;c. may have one moyety of the ſaid forfeitures, accord<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing to the form of the Statute aforeſaid: And alſo that he, the ſaid D. S. may come here into Court to anſwer the premiſes, &amp;c.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="precedent">
                  <head>
                     <hi>Againſt ſelling Flour and Meal in ſhops, An Information upon an Act of Parliament,</hi> 1650.</head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Middl.</hi> ſſ. BE it remembred, that H. M. who as well for the poor of the Pariſh of M. in the ſaid County as for himſelf in this behalf, proſecutes; came here into Court the firſt day of <hi>Fe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bruary,</hi> in the year of our Lord, 1656. in his own perſon and as well for the poor of the ſaid Pariſh as for himſelf, gave the Court here to underſtand and be informed, that one I. C. late of the
<pb n="36" facs="tcp:170677:22"/> Pariſh of M. aforeſaid, in the ſaid Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty, between the 29 of <hi>September</hi> laſt paſt, and the day of the Exhibiting this In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>formation, at the Pariſh aforeſaid, in the County aforeſaid, did fell and utter, or cauſe to be ſold and uttered to divers perſons whoſe names to the ſaid H. M. who, &amp;c. as yet are unknown, at divers and ſeveral times, and by divers and ſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>veral parcels and quantities, ten quar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ters of wheaten Meal, price of every quarter thereof thirty ſhillings; and ten quarters of wheaten Flour, price of every quarter thereof forty ſhillings, in the Houſe or Shop of the ſaid I. C. and not in any common or publike Market<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>place appointed for the ſelling of Meal and Flour: contrary to the form of a certain Act of the late Seſſions of Par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liament holden at <hi>Weſtminſter,</hi> in the County of <hi>Middleſex, Intituled, An Act touching Corn and Meal made and pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vided;</hi> By means whereof, he the ſaid I. C. hath forfeited to the poor of the ſaid Pariſh, and to the ſaid H. M. who as well, &amp;c. the ſum of threeſcore and fifteen pounds of lawful money of <hi>Eng<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>land,</hi> That is to ſay, treble the value of
<pb n="37" facs="tcp:170677:22"/> the ſaid Meal and Flour, ſo by him in manner and form aforeſaid, and con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>trary to the form of the Act aforeſaid ſold and uttered as aforeſaid: Where<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>upon the ſaid H. M. as well for the poor of the ſaid Pariſh as for himſelf, pray<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>eth the advice of the Court here in the premiſes: And that due proceſs of Law may be awarded againſt him the ſaid I. C. in this behalf; And that he, the ſaid H. M. may have one moyety of the for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>feitures aforeſaid, and that the poor of the ſaid Pariſh may have the other moyety. And that he, the ſaid I. C. may ſuffer impriſonment of his body, for the ſpace of one moneth, according to the form of the Act aforeſaid: And more<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>over, that he come into Court here to anſwer the premiſes, &amp;c.</p>
               </div>
            </div>
            <div type="statute">
               <pb n="38" facs="tcp:170677:23"/>
               <head>Againſt Uſury and Extor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion, An Act of Parlia<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment was made the eighth day of <hi>Auguſt,</hi> 1651. Intituled,
<q>An Act prohibiting any perſon to take above the rate of ſix pounds for the Loan of one hundred pounds by year, and after that rate for a greater or leſſer ſum, or for a ſhorter or longer time.</q>
               </head>
               <div type="precedent">
                  <head>An Information upon the Act againſt Uſury.</head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Middl.</hi> ſſ. BE it remembred, that I. T. who as well for the Lord Protector of the Commonwealth of <hi>England, Scotland,</hi> and <hi>Ireland,</hi> and the Dominions thereunto belonging, as for himſelf in this behalf, proſecutes; came here into Court the twenty fourth day of <hi>April,</hi> 1657. in his own perſon, and as well for the ſaid Lord Protector as for himſelf, gave the Court here to un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>derſtand and be informed, that one I.
<pb n="39" facs="tcp:170677:23"/> M. late of the Pariſh of T. in the ſaid County Yeoman, between the four and twentieth day of <hi>June,</hi> laſt paſt, and the day of the Exhibiting this Information at the Pariſh of T. aforeſaid, in the County aforeſaid, hath by way and means of corrupt bargain, Loan, Ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>change, Chivance, and Shifts, by de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceitful ways and means, and by Covin lent, or put to Loan, to ſeveral perſons whoſe names to the ſaid <hi>John,</hi> who as well, &amp;c. as yet are unknown, divers and ſundry ſum and ſums of money, in the whole amounting to the ſum of two hundred pounds of lawful money of <hi>England;</hi> And the ſaid I. T. as well for the ſaid Lord Protector as for himſelf, will verifie that the ſaid I. M. hath indi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rectly for the forbearing or giving day of payment for the ſaid ſum of two hun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dred pounds for one whole year, taken above the ſum of ſix pounds for every hundred pounds thereof, againſt the form of a certain Act of Parliament, holden at <hi>Weſtminſter,</hi> in the County of <hi>Middleſex,</hi> on <hi>Friday</hi> the eighth day of <hi>Auguſt,</hi> 1651. Intituled, <hi>An Act pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>hibiting any perſon to take above ſix pounds</hi>
                     <pb n="40" facs="tcp:170677:24"/> 
                     <hi>for Loan of one hundred pounds by the year, and after that rate for a greater or leſſer ſum, or for a longer or ſhorter time:</hi> By means whereof, the ſaid I. M. hath for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>feited to the ſaid Lord Protector, and to the ſaid I. T. who as well, &amp;c. ſix hundred pounds of lawful money of <hi>England,</hi> That is to ſay, treble the va<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lue of the ſaid money, ſo by him in form aforeſaid, and againſt the form of the Act aforeſaid, lent or put to Loan. Whereupon the ſaid I. T. as well for the ſaid Lord Protector as for himſelf, pray<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>eth the advice of the Court here in the premiſes: And that the ſaid I. T. who as well, &amp;c. may have the moyety of the ſaid forfeitures, according to the form of the Act aforeſaid: And alſo, that the ſaid I. M. may come here into Court to anſwer the premiſes, &amp;c.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="precedent">
                  <head>Another form of an Information upon the ſame Act.</head>
                  <p>L. ſſ. BE it remembred, that I. S. who as well for the now Lord Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tector of the Commonwealth of <hi>Eng<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                        <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="4 letters">
                           <desc>••••</desc>
                        </gap>
                        <g ref="char:punc">▪</g>
                     </hi> as for himſelf in this behalf, proſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cutes;
<pb n="41" facs="tcp:170677:24"/> came here into Court the ſeven<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>teenth day of <hi>April,</hi> this Term, in his own perſon, and as well for the ſaid Lord Protector as for himſelf, gave the Court here to underſtand and be infor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>med, that one I. H. late of <hi>London,</hi> Sad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ler, between the nine and twentieth day of <hi>September</hi> laſt paſt, and the day of the Exhibiting this Information, for the lu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cre and gain of the ſaid I. H. at <hi>London</hi> aforeſaid, to wit, in the Pariſh of bleſſed <hi>Mary Bow,</hi> and Ward of Cheap, did in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>directly, and by way of corrupt bargain, and contract, Lend upon Uſury, Loan, and Intereſt, at one ſum, or by divers and ſeveral ſums and parcels, and to one perſon or divers ſeveral perſons, whoſe names to the ſaid I. S. who as well, &amp;c. as yet are unknown, fifty pounds of law<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ful money of <hi>England;</hi> And the ſaid I. H. the Act of Parliament aforeſaid, or the penalties in the ſame little regarding, did corruptly and indirectly receive and take of the ſaid one perſon or of the ſaid ſeveral perſons, for the Uſe and Intereſt of every twenty ſhillings of the ſaid fif<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty pounds, for the Loan of the ſame, for the ſpace of twenty weeks, the ſum of
<pb n="42" facs="tcp:170677:25"/> two ſhillings; In the whole amounting after that rate, to the ſum of five pounds, for the Uſe and Intereſt of the ſaid fifty pounds, for the ſaid twenty weeks. And the ſaid I. S. as well for the ſaid Lord Protector as for himſelf, will verifie, that the ſaid I. H. did alſo receive and take, of the ſaid one perſon or of ſeveral perſons, the ſaid fifty pounds by one ſum or ſeveral ſums paid weekly, ſo that the ſame was fully paid within the ſaid twenty weeks, contrary to the form of a certain Act of the late Seſſions of Par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liament, holden at <hi>Weſtminſter,</hi> in the County of <hi>Middleſex,</hi> on <hi>Friday</hi> the eighth day of <hi>Auguſt,</hi> 1651. Intituled, <hi>An Act prohibiting any perſon to take above the rate of ſix pounds, for the forbearance of an hundred pounds for a whole year, and ſo after that rate for a greater or leſſer ſum, or for a longer or ſhorter time:</hi> By means whereof, the ſaid I. H. hath forfeited to the ſaid Lord Protector and to the ſaid I. S. who as well, &amp;c. the ſum of an hun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dred and fifty pounds of lawful money of <hi>England,</hi> That is to ſay, treble the va<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lue of the money ſo by him lent, upon corrupt Uſury and Extortion in manner
<pb n="43" facs="tcp:170677:25"/> and form aforeſaid, and againſt the form of the Act aforeſaid: Whereupon the ſaid I. S. as well for the ſaid Lord Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tector as for himſelf, prayeth the advice of the Court here in the premiſes, and that he, the ſaid I. S. who as well, &amp;c. may have one moyety of the ſaid forfei<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tures, according to the form of the Act aforeſaid: And alſo, that he the ſaid I. H. may come here into Court to anſwer in and upon the premiſes, &amp;c. Pledges of proſecuting, &amp;c. <hi>John Doo</hi> and <hi>Richard Roo,</hi> &amp;c.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="declaration">
                  <head>For the Brokers and Uſurers ſakes, I will here lay down the form of a De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>claration in an Action of Debt upon the ſaid Statute.</head>
                  <p>L. ſſ. G. S. late of <hi>London,</hi> Gentlem. was ſummoned to anſwer unto I. T. who as well for the now Lord Protector, &amp;c. as for himſelf in this be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>half proſecutes, of a Plea, that he ren<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der unto the ſaid Lord Protector and to the ſaid I. T. who as well, &amp;c. ſix hun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dred pounds of lawful money of <hi>Eng<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>land,</hi> which unto the ſaid Lord Prote<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ctor,
<pb n="44" facs="tcp:170677:26"/> and unto the ſaid I. T. who as well, &amp;c. he oweth, and unju<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>tly detaineth, &amp;c. And whereupon the ſaid I. T. as well for the ſaid L. Pr. as for himſelf, by R. T. his Attorney, ſaith, That whereas in the Parliament, holden at <hi>Weſtminſter,</hi> in the County of <hi>Middl.</hi> on <hi>Friday</hi> the eighth day of <hi>Auguſt,</hi> in the year of our Lord, 1651. It was Enacted, Eſtabliſhed, and Ordained by the ſame Parliament, and by the Authority thereof, That no per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon or perſons whatſoever ſhould from and after the twenty ninth of <hi>September</hi> then next following; directly or indi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rectly, or by means of any corrupt bar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gain, Loan, Exchange, Chivance, or Shifts, or by any deceitful ways or means whatſoever, receive or take for the forbearance, or giving day of payment for any ſum or ſums of money, Goods, Wares, or Merchandize, above the ſum of ſix pounds for the forbearance, or gi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ving day of payment for the ſum of one hundred pounds for one whole year; and ſo after that rate for a greater or leſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſer ſum, or for a ſhorter or longer time, on pain of the forfeiture of treble the value of the ſaid Money, Goods, Wares,
<pb n="45" facs="tcp:170677:26"/> or Merchandize, lent or put to Loan, contrary to the form and effect of the Act aforeſaid; one moyety of which for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>feitures to be to the uſe of the then Keepers of the Liberty of <hi>England,</hi> &amp;c. and their Succeſſors, the other moyety to any perſon that ſhould ſue for the ſame in any Court or Courts of Record: wherein no Wager of Law, Eſſoyn, or other Protection is to be allowed. And thereupon the ſaid I. T. in fact, ſaith, That the ſaid G. S. the Act of Parlia<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment aforeſaid or the penalties in the ſame little regarding, hath ſince the publiſhing of the ſaid Act of Parliament, to wit, the twenty fourth day of <hi>June,</hi> in the year of our Lord, 1656. at <hi>Lon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>don</hi> aforeſaid, That is to ſay, in the Pa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riſh of Saint <hi>Mary Bow,</hi> and the Ward of Cheap, by ways and means of Cor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rupt bargain, Loan, Exchange, Chi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vance, and Shifts, by deceitful ways and means, and by Covin, Lent or put to Loan, to ſeveral perſons, whoſe names to the ſaid I. T. who as well, &amp;c. as yet are unknown; divers and ſundry ſum and ſums of money, in the whole a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mounting to the ſum of two hundred
<pb n="46" facs="tcp:170677:27"/> pounds of lawful money of <hi>England;</hi> And the ſaid I. T. as well for the ſaid Lord Protector as for himſelf, will ve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rifie that the ſaid I. M. hath indirectly for the forbearing or giving day of pay<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment, for one whole year for the ſaid ſum of two hundred pounds, taken a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bove the ſum of ſix pounds for every hundred pounds thereof, againſt the form of the Act aforeſaid in this Caſe made and provided. Whereby an Acti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on hath accrued to the ſaid L. Protector and to the ſaid I. T. who as well, &amp;c. to have and receive of the ſaid G. S. the ſum of ſix hundred pounds of lawful money of <hi>England,</hi> That is to ſay, tre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble the value of the ſaid money ſo by him in manner and form aforeſaid, and againſt the form of the Act aforeſaid, Lent or put to Loan: yet the ſaid G. S. though often required, the ſaid ſix hun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dred pounds to the ſaid, &amp;c. hath not paid, &amp;c. to the damage, &amp;c.</p>
               </div>
            </div>
            <div type="statute">
               <pb n="47" facs="tcp:170677:27"/>
               <head>Clothiers and Drapery.</head>
               <epigraph>
                  <bibl>Stat. 4. <hi>E</hi> 4. 1.</bibl>
                  <q>None ſhall put into Cloth to be ſold any Lambs-wooll, Flocks, or Cork in pain to forfeit twenty ſhillings for every Cloth or half Cloth ſo mingled, to be di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vided betwixt the King and the proſecu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tor.</q>
               </epigraph>
               <div type="precedent">
                  <head>An Information againſt Clothiers, for making Cloth of mingled ſtuff.</head>
                  <p>L. ſſ. IT is to be remembred, that I. B. who as well for the now Lord Protector of <hi>England, Scotland,</hi> and <hi>Ire<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>land,</hi> and the Dominions thereunto be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>longing, as for himſelf in this behalf, doth proſecute; came here into Court the ſeventh day of <hi>June,</hi> in the year of our Lord 1657. in his own perſon, and as well for the now Lord Protector as for himſelf, gave the Court here to un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>derſtand and be informed, that one G. S. late of <hi>London,</hi> Clothier, between the firſt day of <hi>Auguſt</hi> laſt paſt, and the day of the Exhibiting this Information at
<pb n="48" facs="tcp:170677:28"/> 
                     <hi>London,</hi> That is to ſay, in the Pariſh of bleſſed <hi>Mary Bow,</hi> and Ward of Cheap, uſing and exerciſing the Trade, Art, and Myſtery of a Clothier, did uſe to mix with his Wool for the making of Wool<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>len-clothes, Kerſeys, and Bays, Lambs-wooll, and Flocks, and other deceitful ſtuff, and within the time aforeſaid, at <hi>London</hi> aforeſaid, in the Pariſh and Ward aforeſaid, he the ſaid G. S. twenty broad Woollen clothes, twenty Ker<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſeys, and twenty pieces of Bays, with the ſaid Lambs-wooll, and Flocks, and other deceitful mingled ſtuff, did make and put to ſale, contrary to the form of the Statute in ſuch Caſe made and pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vided; By means whereof, he the ſaid G. S. hath forfeited to the ſaid Lord Protector, and to the ſaid I. B. who as well, &amp;c. the ſum of threeſcore pounds of lawful money of <hi>England,</hi> That is to ſay, the ſum of twenty ſhillings for e<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>very Woollen-cloth, Kerſey, and Bays of the ſaid twenty ſeveral pieces of Woollen-cloth, Kerſey, and Bays ſo by him of deceitful mingled ſtuff made as aforeſaid, in the whole amounting af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter that rate to the ſaid threeſcore
<pb n="49" facs="tcp:170677:28"/> pounds: Whereupon the ſaid I. B. as well for the ſaid Lord Protector as for himſelf, prayeth the advice of the Court here in the premiſes, and that due pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceſs of Law may be awarded againſt him the ſaid G. S. here in the premiſes: And that he, the ſaid I. B. may have one moy<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ety of the forfeitures aforeſaid, accord<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing to the form of the Statute aforeſaid: and that he, the ſaid G. S. may come here into Court to anſwer the premiſes, &amp;c.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="precedent">
                  <head>An Information againſt Drapers for ſtretching and tentoring Cloth after it is wrought.</head>
                  <p>L. ſſ. IT. is to be remembred, that I. S. who as well for the Lord Prote<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ctor, &amp;c. as for himſelf in this behalf, proſecutes; came here into Court the ſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>venteenth day of <hi>June,</hi> in the year of our Lord, 1657. in his own perſon, and as well for the ſaid Lord Protector as for himſelf, gave the Court here to under<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtand and be informed, that one R. C. late of <hi>London,</hi> Draper, between the firſt day of <hi>Auguſt</hi> laſt paſt, and the day
<pb n="50" facs="tcp:170677:29"/> of the Exhibiting this Information at <hi>London</hi> aforeſaid, to wit, in the Pariſh of Saint <hi>Mary Bow,</hi> and Ward of Cheap, uſing and exerciſing the Art and Trade of a Draper, did uſe certain Tentors, and other Engines, for the ſetting, ſtretching, and ſtreining of Woollen-clothes, Kerſeys, and Bays, after the ſame was fully Watered, Milled and Wrought, and Rowen: And within the time aforeſaid, at <hi>London</hi> aforeſaid, in the Pariſh and Ward aforeſaid, did by tentoring and other deceitful Engines and Ways, ſet or draw in length above one yard, and in breadth above one half quarter of a yard, above the length and breadth the ſame was made at, when it was fully watered and wrought: ten broad Woollen-clothes, price of every Cloth thereof ten pounds; ten Kerſeys, price of every Kerſey thereof five pounds, ten pieces of Bays, price of every piece thereof four pounds; with the ſaid Tentors and other deceitful Engines as aforeſaid, contrary to the form of the Statute in this Caſe made and provided; By means whereof<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> he, the ſaid R. C. hath
<pb n="51" facs="tcp:170677:29"/> forfeited to the ſaid Lord Protector and the ſaid I. S. who as well, &amp;c. the ſum of an hundred fourſcore and ten pounds of lawful money of <hi>England,</hi> That is to ſay, the value of the ſaid Woollen-clothes, Kerſeys, and Bays, ſo by him in manner and form aforeſaid, and againſt the form of the Statute aforeſaid, with the ſaid Tentors and other Engines as aforeſaid, after the ſame was fully wa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tered, wrought, and rowen, ſet and drawn in length and breadth as afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid: Whereupon the ſaid I. S. as well for the ſaid Lord Protector as for him<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelf, prayeth the advice of the Court here in the premiſes; and that due pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceſs of Law, &amp;c. And that he, the ſaid I. S. who as well, &amp;c. may have one moy<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ety of the ſaid forfeitures, according to the form of the Statute, &amp;c: and that he, the ſaid R. C. may come here in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>to Court to anſwer the premiſes, &amp;c.</p>
                  <argument>
                     <p>This laſt Information is upon the <hi>Statute of 1. R. 3. 8.</hi> where there is alſo a Penalty of twenty pounds upon any Draper, that ſhall keep in his houſe any Te<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>tor or o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther Engine, to draw Cloth in length or
<pb n="52" facs="tcp:170677:30"/> breadth, after it is fully watered or wrought. Which forfeitures are to be divided betwixt the King and the pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſecutor.</p>
                  </argument>
               </div>
            </div>
            <div type="statute">
               <head>Againſt making Clothes of mixed ſtuff.</head>
               <epigraph>
                  <bibl>Stat. 43. <hi>Eliz.</hi> 10.</bibl>
                  <q>
                     <p>None ſhall put any Hair, Flocks, Thrum, Yarn, made of Lambs-wooll, or any other deceivable thing, in Broad-cloth, Kerſey, Frize, Dozen Peniſtone, Cotton, Taunton-Cloth, Bridgewater, or Dunſter-Cotton<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> in pain to forfeit ſuch Cloth, Kerſey, &amp;c. And none ſhall buy or procure any ſuch deceivable thing for that intent, in pain to forfeit the ſame.</p>
                     <p>None ſhall uſe any Engine to ſtretch the ſaid Clothes or Rugs, unwrought, in length or breadth, on paid of twenty pounds, to be divided between the Queen and the proſecutor.</p>
                     <p>
                        <hi>None ſhall ſet any wrought Wool<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>len<g ref="char:punc">▪</g>clo<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                              <desc>•</desc>
                           </gap>h upon any Tentor or other En<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gine, to ſtretch the ſame otherwiſe then</hi>
                        <pb n="53" facs="tcp:170677:30"/> 
                        <hi>as followeth,</hi> viz. <hi>the whole Broad-cloth one yard in length, and one half quarter in breadth; and the Kerſey, Cotton, &amp;c. one half yard in length, and one nail in breadth, in pain to forfeit ſuch Cloth, Kerſey, &amp;c.</hi>
                     </p>
                  </q>
               </epigraph>
               <p>The Forms of the Information upon theſe Statutes, are before recited, &amp;c.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="statute">
               <head>If I ſhould forget the Brewer and Alehouſe-keeper, I know they would be of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fended. Therefore</head>
               <epigraph>
                  <bibl>Stat. 4. <hi>Jam.</hi> 4.</bibl>
                  <q>None ſhall ſell Ale or Beer to an unli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cenſed Alehouſe-keeper, ſave onely for the expence of his houſhold, in pain of ſix ſhillings and eight pence for eve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry Barrel, and ſo more or leſs accord<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing to that proportion; which forfei<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tures ſhall be equally divided between the Informer and the poor of the pariſh.</q>
               </epigraph>
               <div type="precedent">
                  <pb n="54" facs="tcp:170677:31"/>
                  <head>An Information againſt Brewers ſer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ving an unlicenſed Alehouſe with Beer and Ale.</head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Middl.</hi> ſſ. BE it remembred, that I. S. who as well for the poor of the Pariſh of B. in the ſaid County as for himſelf in this behalf, proſecutes; came here into Court the twelfth day of <hi>February,</hi> in the year of our Lord, one thouſand ſix hundred and fifty ſix, in his own perſon, and as well for the poor of the ſaid Pariſh of B. as for him<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelf, gives the Court here to underſtand and be informed, that one I. R. late of the Pariſh of B. in the ſaid County, Brewer, between the firſt day of <hi>March</hi> laſt paſt, and the day of the Exhibiting this Information, at the Pariſh of B. aforeſaid, in the County aforeſaid, did ſell, utter, and ſerve to one certain per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon, or to divers certain perſons, whoſe names to the ſaid I. S. who as well, &amp;c. as yet are unknown, to ſell the ſame again without Licenſe, forty Barrels of ſtrong Beer, and forty Barrels of ſtrong
<pb n="55" facs="tcp:170677:31"/> Ale, to be ſold again in the houſe or houſes of the ſaid perſon or perſons, ha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ving no Licenſe to Authorize them thereunto; And the ſaid I. S. as well for the ſaid poor of the Pariſh of B. aforeſaid as for himſelf, will verifie, That the ſaid I. R. did wittingly, and of his own knowledge, ſell, and utter the ſaid Beer and Ale to the ſaid houſe or houſes, knowing the ſame was to be ſold again and uttered by retail by the ſaid perſon or perſons without Licenſe: And that the ſame Beer and Ale within the time aforeſaid, at the dwelling houſes of the ſaid perſon or perſons, was ſold and uttered againſt the form of the Statute in this Caſe made and provided: By means whereof, he, the ſaid I. R. hath forfeited to the poor of the ſaid Pariſh, and to the ſaid I. S. who as well, &amp;c. the ſum of ſix and twenty pounds thir<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>teen ſhillings and four pence, That is to ſay, for every Barrel of the ſaid Beer and Ale ſold by him in manner and form a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>foreſaid, to unlicenſed Alehouſes a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>foreſaid, againſt the form of the Statute aforeſaid, ſold and uttered, the ſum of ſix ſhillings and eight pence, in the
<pb n="56" facs="tcp:170677:32"/> whole amounting after that rate to the ſaid ſix and twenty pounds thirteen ſhillings and four pence; whereupon the ſaid I. S. as well for the poor of the ſaid Pariſh as for himſelf, prayeth the ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vice of the Court here in the premiſes, and that due proceſs of Law, &amp;c. And that he the ſaid I. S. who, &amp;c. may have one moyety of the ſaid forfeitures ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cording to the form of the Statute a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>foreſaid: And alſo, that he the ſaid I. R. may come here into Court to anſwer the premiſes, &amp;c.</p>
               </div>
            </div>
            <div type="statute">
               <head>Butchers.</head>
               <epigraph>
                  <bibl>Statute 4. <hi>H.</hi> 7. 3.</bibl>
                  <q>
                     <hi>No Butcher ſhall kill any Fleſh in his ſcalding houſe, or within the Walls of</hi> London, <hi>in pain to forfeit for every Ox ſo killed twelve pence; and for every o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther beaſt eight pence, to be divided be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tween the King and the proſecutor.</hi>
                  </q>
               </epigraph>
               <div type="precedent">
                  <pb n="57" facs="tcp:170677:32"/>
                  <head>
                     <hi>An Information againſt Butchers for killing Fleſh within the Walls of</hi> London.</head>
                  <p>L. ſſ. BE it remembred, that I. S. who as well for the now Lord Protector of <hi>England, Scotland,</hi> and <hi>Ire<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>land,</hi> and the Dominions thereunto be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>longing, as for himſelf in this behalf, proſecutes; came here into Court the ſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>venteenth day of <hi>June,</hi> in the year of our Lord, 1657. in his own perſon; and as well for the ſaid Lord Protector as for himſelf, gave the Court here to under<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtand and be informed, that one A. B. late of <hi>London,</hi> Butcher, between the twenty ninth day of <hi>Septemb.</hi> laſt paſt, and the day of the Exhibiting this Infor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mation at <hi>London</hi> aforeſaid, to wit, in the Pariſh of &amp;c. within the Walls and Liberties of the City of <hi>London</hi> afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid, did keep a common Slaughter-houſe for the killing of Cattle; and between the time aforeſaid, at <hi>London</hi> aforeſaid, in the Pariſh and Ward aforeſaid, with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>in the Walls and Liberties of the City of <hi>London</hi> aforeſaid, did kill four hun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dred
<pb n="58" facs="tcp:170677:33"/> Oxen, ſix hundred Sheep, two hun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dred Prokers, two hundred Calves, and two hundred Lambs; to the great an<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>noyance of the Pariſhioners of the Pa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riſh aforeſaid, and againſt the form of the Statute in this Caſe made and provided: By means whereof, he the ſaid A. B. hath forfeited to the ſaid Lord Prote<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ctor, and to the ſaid I. S. who as well, &amp;c. the ſum of threeſcore pounds of lawful money of <hi>England,</hi> That is to ſay, for every Ox of the ſaid four hundred Oxen ſo by him in manner and form aforeſaid, and againſt the form of the Statute aforeſaid, killed, the ſum of twelve pence; and for every other Beaſt aforeſaid, by him killed as aforeſaid, within the Walls of the City of <hi>London</hi> aforeſaid, contrary to the form of the Statute aforeſaid, the ſum of eight pence of like lawful money of <hi>England;</hi> in the whole amounting after that rate to the ſaid threeſcore pounds: Whereupon the ſaid I. S. as well, &amp;c. prayeth the ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vice, &amp;c. and that due proceſs of Law, &amp;c. And that he, the ſaid I. S. who as well, &amp;c. may have the moyety of the forfeitures aforeſaid, according to the
<pb n="59" facs="tcp:170677:33"/> form of the Statute aforeſaid; and that he the ſaid A. B. may come here into Court to anſwer the premiſes, &amp;c.</p>
               </div>
            </div>
            <div type="statute">
               <head>Againſt Butchers for buying Cattle, and ſelling them again alive.</head>
               <bibl>Stat. 3. &amp;. 4. <hi>E.</hi> 19.</bibl>
               <p>BE it remembred, that I. S. who as well for the now L. Protector, &amp;c. as for himſelf in this behalf, proſecutes; came here into Court the ſeventeenth day of <hi>June,</hi> in the year of our Lord, 1657. in his own perſon, and as well for the ſaid Lord Protector as for himſelf, gave the Court here to underſtand and be informed, that one I. R. late of <hi>Lon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>don,</hi> Butcher, between the firſt day of <hi>Auguſt</hi> laſt paſt, and the day of the Ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>hibiting this information at <hi>London</hi> a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>foreſaid, to wit, in the Pariſh of Saint <hi>Mary Bow,</hi> and Ward, did buy of ſever<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>al perſons, whoſe names to the ſaid I. S. &amp;c. as yet are unknown, ten Oxen, price of every Ox ten pounds; twenty
<pb n="60" facs="tcp:170677:34"/> Sheep, price of every Sheep twenty ſhil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lings; twenty Calves, price of every Calf thereof twenty ſhillings; and twen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty Lambs, price of every Lamb ten ſhil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lings. And the ſaid I. R. afterwards, between the time aforeſaid, at <hi>London</hi> a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>foreſaid, in the Pariſh and Ward afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid, did ſell the ſaid ſeveral Cattle a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gain alive to ſeveral perſons, whoſe names to the ſaid I. S. who, &amp;c. as yet are unknown, againſt the form of the Statute in this Caſe made and provided: By means whereof he, the ſaid I. R. hath forfeited to the ſaid Lord Protector, and to the ſaid I. R. who, &amp;c. the ſum of an hundred and ten pounds of lawful money of <hi>England,</hi> That is to ſay, the value of the ſaid Cattle ſo by him in manner and form aforeſaid, and againſt the form of the Statute aforeſaid, bought and ſold again alive as aforeſaid: Where<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>upon the ſaid I. S. as well for the ſaid Lord Protector as for himſelf, prayeth the advice of the Court here in the pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſes, and that due proceſs of Law may be awarded againſt him the ſaid I. R. &amp;c. And that he the ſaid I. S. who, &amp;c. may have one moyety of the ſaid forfeitures,
<pb n="61" facs="tcp:170677:34"/> according to the form of the Statute aforeſaid: And moreover, that he the ſaid I. R. may come here into Court to anſwer in and upon the premiſes, &amp;c.</p>
               <div type="subpoena">
                  <head>A Subpaena upon an Information.</head>
                  <p>OLIVER, Lord Protector, &amp;c. to I. B. and C. D. greeting. We com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mand you, that all other occaſions pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>termitted, and excuſes whatſoever cea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſing; you appear in your own perſons before our Juſtices of the Common Bench at <hi>Weſtminſter,</hi> on <hi>Fryday</hi> next af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter three weeks of Saint <hi>Michael,</hi> to an<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſwer us, of, and concerning ſuch things as ſhall then and there be objected a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gainſt you on our behalf: and further to do and receive what our ſaid Court ſhall conſider thereof in this behalf: And this you ſhall not omit on pain of an hundred pounds: And have you there this Writ; witneſs, &amp;c. <hi>Pinſent.</hi>
                  </p>
                  <p>On the backſide of the Writ indorſe the Informers Name, and the Statute on which the Action is grounded: or if there be ſeveral Informations, then thus.</p>
                  <p>I. S. proſecutes this writ upon the breach of ſeveral Statutes.</p>
                  <pb n="62" facs="tcp:170677:35"/>
                  <p> Then if the Defendant appear not, Affidavit being made that the Subpaena was ſerved, an attachment is awarded againſt him to arreſt his body; and he muſt pay coſts to the Informer before he can enter his appearance, which coſts is to be allowed by a Judge or Ju<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtice of the Court where the Informati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on is brought.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="precedent">
                  <head>An Information for buying of pretend<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed Titles.</head>
                  <bibl>Le Stat. de 32. <hi>H.</hi> 8. cap. 9.</bibl>
                  <p>S. ſſ. G. B. who as well for the Lord the King, as for himſelf fol<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>loweth; came here into Court the twelfth day of <hi>February,</hi> this ſame Term in his own perſon: And as well, &amp;c. as for himſelf, gave the Court here to un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>derſtand and be informed, that whereas one I. W. the twentieth day of <hi>May,</hi> in the year, &amp;c. and by the ſpace of two years then laſt paſt, was ſeized in his demeaſne, as of Fee, of and in one Meſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſuage with the appurtenances in G. in the County aforeſaid, of the value of ſix<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty pounds: And the ſaid I. W. by all the
<pb n="63" facs="tcp:170677:35"/> time aforeſaid, the iſſues and profits of the ſaid Meſſuage with the appurtenan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ces, had and received to his own pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>per uſe: Nevertheleſs one I. O. the ſaid twentieth day of <hi>May,</hi> in the year afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid, did Enfeoffe one R. O. his bro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther, of the Meſſuage aforeſaid with the appurtenances, to hold to him and his Heirs for ever: And the ſaid <hi>Richard</hi> the ſaid twentieth day of <hi>May,</hi> in the year aforeſaid, at G. aforeſaid, knowing the ſame, did receive of the ſaid I. O. the Feofment aforeſaid, of the Meſſuage a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>foreſaid, with the appurtenances to him and his Heirs in the form aforeſaid made, whereas neither the ſaid I. O. nor any of his Anceſtors, nor he nor they by whom the ſaid I. O. claimed the Meſſuage aforeſaid, with the appurte<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nances, were in poſſeſſion, nor in ſeized reverſion thereof, neither did he or they receive the rents or profits of the ſame Meſſuage by the ſpace of one whole year next before the ſaid Feofment by the ſaid I. O. to the ſaid R. O. ſo there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>of made: And by the aforeſaid R. of the ſaid I. as aforeſaid, received againſt the form of the Statute in this Caſe
<pb n="64" facs="tcp:170677:36"/> made and provided: Whereby the ſaid I. O. hath forfeited ſixty pounds, that is to ſay, the value of the ſaid Meſſuage with the appurtenances, by him, againſt the form of the Statute aforeſaid to the aforeſaid R. in the form aforeſaid enfe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>offed: And likewiſe the ſaid <hi>Richard</hi> hath forfeited ſixty pounds for the ſaid value of the Meſſuage aforeſaid, with the appurtenances, by the ſaid <hi>Richard,</hi> againſt the form of the Statute aforeſaid, of the ſaid I. O. by the Feofment afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid, as aforeſaid taken: Whereupon the ſaid G. B. who as well, &amp;c, prayeth that he may have the moyeties of the ſeveral forfeitures aforeſaid, according to the form of the Statute aforeſaid; and as well for the ſaid Lord the King as for himſelf, prayeth the advice of the Court here in the premiſes: And that due proceſs of Law may be awarded a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gainſt the ſaid I O. and R. O. in this be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>half, and that the ſaid I. and R. may come here into Court to anſwer, as well the ſaid Lord the King, as the ſaid G. who, &amp;c. in and upon the premiſes, &amp;c. <bibl>
                        <hi>Hill.</hi> 2. <hi>Jac. rot.</hi> 2933. <hi>com. Banco.</hi>
                     </bibl>
                  </p>
               </div>
            </div>
            <div type="precedent">
               <pb n="65" facs="tcp:170677:36"/>
               <head>For buying of pretended Ti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tles, Stat. 39. <hi>H.</hi> 8. cap. 9. An Information in the up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>per Bench, and iſſue there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>upon <hi>inter placita Coronae,</hi> 19 &amp; 20. <hi>Eliz.</hi> Rot. 28.</head>
               <p>K. ſſ. BE it remembred, that T. W. who as well for the Lady the Queen as for himſelf in this behalf, pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſecutes; giveth the Court of our Lady the Queen here to under and and be informed, that whereas by a certain Act in the Parliament of the Lord <hi>Henry</hi> the eighth, late King of <hi>England,</hi> begun at <hi>Weſtminſter</hi> the twenty eighth day of <hi>A<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pril,</hi> in the one and thirtieth year of his Reign, and afterwards continued by divers prorogations until the twelfth day of <hi>April</hi> then next following, and from thence held until the eleventh day of <hi>May</hi> then next following, and from thence continued by prorogation until the fifth day of <hi>May</hi> then next follow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing,
<pb n="66" facs="tcp:170677:37"/> and then held till the twenty fourth day of <hi>July,</hi> in the two and thirtieth year of his Reign; It was Enacted a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mongſt other things by the Authority of the ſaid Parliament, That no perſon or perſons, of what degree, eſtate, quality, or condition ſoever, he or they be, from that time forwards, ſhould bargain, buy, or ſell, or by any way or means, ſhall obtain, acquire, or have, by any pretence any Rights or Titles, or ſhall take or receive any promiſe, grant, or conveyance, to have any Right or Ti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tle of any perſon or perſons in or to any Mannors, Lands, Tenements, or He<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>reditaments, unleſs ſuch perſon or per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons which ſhall ſo bargain, ſell, give grant, convey, or promiſe the ſame, or his or their Anceſtors by whom he or they claim the ſame, were in poſſeſſion of the ſame, or in the Reverſion or Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mainder thereof, or received the Rents and Profits thereof by the ſpace of one whole year next before the ſaid grant, bargain, conveyance, or promiſe made, upon pain that he who maketh any ſuch bargain, ſale, promiſe, conveyance, or grant, ſhall forfeit the full value of the
<pb n="67" facs="tcp:170677:37"/> Lands, Tenements, or Hereditaments, ſo bargained, ſold, promiſed, conveyed, or granted againſt the form of the ſaid Act: And the buyer or receiver there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>of knowing the ſame, ſhall forfeit alſo the value of the ſaid Lands, Tenements, or Hereditaments, ſo by him bought or received as aforeſaid, one moyety of which ſaid forfeitures ſhall be to the Lord the King, the other moyety to the party that will ſue for the ſame in any Court of Record, by Action of Debt, Bill, Plaint, or Information, in which Action, Bill, Plaint, or Information, no Eſſoyne, Protection, Wager of Law, or Injunction, ſhall be allowed, as in the ſame Act amongſt other things more plainly appears: Nevertheleſs one L. A. of <hi>London,</hi> S. the Statute aforeſaid little regarding, after the publiſhing of the ſaid Act, to wit, the eighteenth day of <hi>May,</hi> in the year, &amp;c. at G. in the County of K. claiming a certain pretended Right and Title to her and her Heirs, of, and in one Meſſuage, two Gardens, two Or<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chards, forty Acres of Land, twenty Acres of Meadow, ten Acres of paſture, and ten Acres of Wood, and twelve
<pb n="66" facs="tcp:170677:38"/>
                  <gap reason="duplicate" extent="1 page">
                     <desc>〈1 page duplicate〉</desc>
                  </gap>
                  <pb n="67" facs="tcp:170677:38"/>
                  <gap reason="duplicate" extent="1 page">
                     <desc>〈1 page duplicate〉</desc>
                  </gap>
                  <pb n="68" facs="tcp:170677:39"/> pence half penny rent, with the appurte<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nances in G. aforeſaid; the Meſſuage a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>foreſaid, and all other the premiſes, with the appurtenances, to one P. W. of <hi>Lon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>don,</hi> Grocer, and his Heirs, did convey; And the ſame R. W. then of, and in the ſame with the appurtenances, by a writing of Feoſment did enfeoffe: of which ſaid Tenements, neither the ſaid S. nor any of her Anceſtors, nor he nor they, by whom ſhe claimeth the ſame Tenements, were in the poſſeſſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on of the ſame, nor in the poſſeſſion of the reverſion or the remainder there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>of, neither received the Rents and Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fits thereof by the ſpace of one whole year next before the ſaid conveyance and Feofment aforeſaid: Nevertheleſs the ſaid R. W. the premiſes well enough knowing, the Statute aforeſaid not re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>garding, at G. aforeſaid, in the County aforeſaid, the eighteenth day of <hi>May</hi> in the year aforeſaid, the Feofment afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid of the ſaid S. did receive, to hold the ſaid pretended Title of the ſaid S. of, and in the aforeſaid Tenements, to the ſame R. and his heirs for ever, a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gainſt the form of the Statute aforeſaid.
<pb n="69" facs="tcp:170677:39"/> By virtue whereof, the ſaid R. W. was ſeized of the ſaid Meſſuage, and all o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther the premiſes with the appurtenan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ces, to him and his heirs, according to the Tenor of the Feofment aforeſaid. And the aforeſaid T. W. ſaith in fact, that the Title of the ſaid S. to the afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid Meſſuages, and all other the pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſes with the appurtenances, at the time of the Feofment aforeſaid thereof by the ſaid R. W. aforeſaid made and received, was pretended: And that the aforeſaid Meſſuages, and all other the premiſes with the appurtenances, at that time, were worth forty pounds of lawful money of <hi>England,</hi> by which an Action hath accrued to the ſaid Lady the Queen, and to the ſame T. W. who as well for the ſaid Lady the Queen as for himſelf in this behalf, proſecutes, to have and receive as well of the ſaid S. A. forty pounds, as of the ſaid R. W. aforeſaid, forty pounds of lawful money of <hi>England,</hi> for the value of the Meſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſuages aforeſaid, and all other the pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſes with the appurtenances, againſt the form of the Statute aforeſaid, taken, granted, and enfeoffed as aforeſaid:
<pb n="70" facs="tcp:170677:40"/> Whereupon the ſaid T. W. prayeth one moyety, according to the form of the ſame Statute, and as well, &amp;c. prayeth the advice of the Court in the premiſes, and due proceſs of Law to be awarded againſt the ſaid S. A. and R. W. in this behalf, to anſwer as well to the ſaid La<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dy the Queen, as to the ſaid T. in the premiſes, &amp;c. Whereby it was com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>manded the Sheriff, that he omit not, but that he attach them, &amp;c. to anſwer, &amp;c. And now, to wit, on <hi>Friday</hi> next af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter the morrow of Saint <hi>Martin,</hi> this ſame Term, before the Lady the Queen at <hi>Weſtminſter,</hi> came the ſaid R. W. by I. M<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> his Attorney: and having heard the Information aforeſaid, ſaith, That the ſaid Lady the Queen, or the ſaid R. W. who as well, &amp;c. ought not any further to trouble him the ſaid R. by occaſion of the Information aforeſaid, becauſe by Proteſtation he ſaith, That the ſaid Meſſuages, Barns, Orchards, forty Acres of Land, twenty Acres of Meadow, ten Acres of Paſture, ten A<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cres of Wood, and twelve pence and one half-peny rent, with the appurte<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nances in the Information aboveſaid
<pb n="71" facs="tcp:170677:40"/> ſpecified, were not of ſo much value as in the Information aforeſaid above is ſuppoſed.</p>
               <p>And for Plea the ſame R. ſaith, That he did not accept of the ſaid S. A. the Feofment aforeſaid, to have any pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tended Right or Title of the ſaid S. of, and in the Tenements aforeſaid, in the Information aforeſaid, ſpecified to the ſame R. and his Aſſigns for ever, againſt the form of the Statute aforeſaid, in manner and form as by the Information aforeſaid above againſt him it is ſup<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poſed: and of this he puts himſelf upon the Country: And G. G. Eſquire At<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>torney General of the Lady the Queen, who for the ſame Lady the Queen in this behalf, proſecutes, ſaith, That the ſaid R. W. did take of the ſaid S. A. the Feofment aforeſaid, to have the pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tended Right and Title of the ſaid S. of, and in the Tenements aforeſaid, in the Information, aforeſaid ſpecified in man<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ner and form as by the Information a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>foreſaid, againſt him above it is ſuppo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſed: And this he prayeth may be in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quired of by the Country, and the ſaid R. W. in like manner, &amp;c. Therefore
<pb n="72" facs="tcp:170677:41"/> let there come a Jury thereof, before the Lady the Queen in eight days of S. <hi>Hil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lary:</hi> Whereſoever, &amp;c. and who, &amp;c. to recognize, &amp;c. becauſe as well, &amp;c. the ſame day is given as well to G. G. who followeth, &amp;c. as to the ſaid R. W. &amp;c.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="precedent">
               <head>Againſt an under-Sheriff for extortion, Stat. 23. <hi>H.</hi> 6. cap. 10.</head>
               <p>
                  <label>Information.</label>
                  <hi>Middl.</hi> ſſ. BE it remembred, that I. E. of <hi>London</hi> Haberdaſher, who as well for the Lady the Queen as for himſelf, in this behalf follows in his own perſon, came into the Court of the Lady the Queen, before the ſame Lady the Queen at <hi>Weſtminſter,</hi> on <hi>Friday</hi> next after fifteen days of Saint <hi>Hillary,</hi> to wit, the firſt day of <hi>February,</hi> in the year, &amp;c. the ſame Term; and as well, &amp;c. gave the Court here to underſtand and be informed, that whereas in a certain Statute in the Parliament holden at <hi>Weſtminster,</hi> in the County of <hi>Middle<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſex,</hi>
                  <pb n="73" facs="tcp:170677:41"/> the twenty fifth day of <hi>February,</hi> in the twenty third year of the late King <hi>Henry</hi> the ſixth, then King of <hi>England,</hi> amongſt other things it was Enacted, That no Sheriff, under-Sheriff, nor any of their Clerks, Coroners, Stewards of Franchiſes, Bayliffs, or Keepers of Pri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons, or any other Officers or Miniſters, by occaſion or colour of their Office, ſhould take any thing by themſelves, nor by any other to their uſe, profit, or advantage, of any perſon by them or any other arreſted or attached; nor of any perſon, nor any other, for the forbear<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ance or hindrance of an arreſt upon his body, or of any other perſon by them or any one of them, by virtue or colour of his Office, to arreſt or attach for a Fine, Fee, Priſon-fee, Manucaption, letting to Bail, or for ſhewing any aſſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtance or favour to any ſuch perſon ar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>reſted, or to be arreſted, for his re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ward or profit, otherwiſe then ſuch as hereafter followeth: That is to ſay, for the Sheriff twenty pence, for the Bayliff that makes the arreſt four pence, to the Gaoler, if he be committed to priſon to his cuſtody, four pence: And that all
<pb n="74" facs="tcp:170677:42"/> Sheriffs, under-Sheriffs, Clerks of She<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riffs, Stewards, or Bayliffs of Liberties, Sergeants, or Bayliffs, and Coroners; ſhall not take any thing by colour of their Office by themſelves, or by any other perſon to their uſe, of any perſon, for making the return of any pannel, and for the Coppy of a pannel, four pence: And that the aforeſaid Sheriffs, and all other Officers and Miniſters a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>foreſaid, ſhall let go at Liberty all and all manner of perſons by them, or by a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny of them arreſted, or being in their cuſtody by virtue of any Writ, Bill, or Warrant in any perſonal Action, or by reaſon of any Indictment of treſpaſs, upon reaſonable ſecurity of ſufficient perſons, having ſufficient within the County where ſuch perſons are ſo to be let to Bayl, or Manucaption, to keep their days in ſuch places where the ſaid Bills, Writs, or Warrants do require. <hi>(Such perſon and perſons, who are or here<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>after ſhall be in their custody by condemna<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion, execution,</hi> Capias utlagatum, <hi>Excom<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>munication, ſecurity of the Peace; and all ſuch perſons, who are or ſhall be committed by any ſpecial command of any Justice, and</hi>
                  <pb n="75" facs="tcp:170677:42"/> 
                  <hi>vagabonds refuſing to ſerve according to the form of the Statute of Labourers, alto<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gether excepted)</hi> And that no Sheriff, nor any of their Officers or Miniſters a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>foreſaid, ſhall take, or cauſe to be taken or made any Obligation for any cauſe before recited, or by colour of their Of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fice, but onely to themſelves, of any perſon, nor by any perſon which ſhall be in their cuſtody by order of Law, but in the name of their office, and under a condition written, that the aforeſaid priſoners ſhall appear at the day in the ſaid Writs, Bills, or Warrants, contain<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed, and in ſuch places where the ſaid Writs, Bills, or Warrants, require: And if any Sheriff aforeſaid, or any Officers or Miniſters aforeſaid, ſhall take any Obligation in any other form, by co<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lour of their Offices, that then ſuch Ob<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ligation ſhall be void: And that they ſhall not take for the making of any ſuch Obligation, Warrant, or Precept, ſo by them to be made above four pence. And alſo, that all Sheriffs, under-Sher<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ffs, Clerks, Bayliffs, Coroners, Stewards, Bayliffs of Franchizes, or any other Of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ficers or Miniſters, who ſhall do con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>trary
<pb n="76" facs="tcp:170677:43"/> to the Ordination aforeſaid in any point, ſhall therefore forfeit forty pounds for every time, that they or a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny of them ſhall Act or do contrary to the ſaid Statute or any point thereof: of which forfeitures the King ſhall have one moyety, to be imployed to the uſe of his houſhold, and no otherwiſe; and the party who will proſecute ſhall have the other moyety, as in the ſame Sta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tute amongſt other things more plainly it is contained: And whereas in the Term of Saint <hi>Hillary,</hi> in the year, &amp;c. one W. M. proſecuted a certain Writ iſſuing out of the ſaid Court of our Lady the Queen, of Pleas, before our ſaid La<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dy the Queen at <hi>Weſtminſter,</hi> in the County of <hi>Middleſex</hi> aforeſaid, to the Sheriff of B. directed; by which Writ the Sheriff was commanded that he ſhould take E. F. I. Y. I. G. and W. C. and them ſafe keep, &amp;c. ſo that he ſhould have their bodies before the ſaid Lady the Queen here at <hi>Weſtminster,</hi> on <hi>Wed<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſday</hi> next after fifteen days of <hi>Easter</hi> then next following, to anſwer the ſaid W. M. in a Plea of treſpaſs, by virtue of which Writ one E. L. Gentleman, the
<pb n="77" facs="tcp:170677:43"/> fifteenth day of <hi>February,</hi> in the year aboveſaid, at <hi>Westminster,</hi> in the Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty of <hi>Middleſex</hi> aforeſaid, then being the under-Sheriff of A. B. Eſquire, then Sheriff of the County of <hi>Berks,</hi> for and in the name of the ſaid A. B. Sheriff of the County aforeſaid, did make four ſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>veral Warrants againſt the ſaid E. F. I. Y. I. G. and W. C. directed to the Bayliff of the hundred of <hi>Reading</hi> and <hi>Theale,</hi> in the ſaid County of <hi>Berks,</hi> to take the ſaid E. F. &amp;c. ſo that he might have their bodies, &amp;c. to anſwer the ſaid W. M. according to the Exigence of the ſaid ſeveral Warrants: And whereas alſo in the Term of the Holy Trinity, in the year, &amp;c. the ſaid W. M. proſecuted an<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>other Writ of our La. the Queen out of the ſaid Court of our La. the Queen here at <hi>Weſt.</hi> to the ſaid Sheriff of the County of B. directed; by which Writ the ſaid Sheriff was likewiſe commanded, that he ſhould take L. G. I. A. I. his wife I. Y. and W. B. and them ſafe keep, &amp;c. ſo that he ſhould have their bodies, &amp;c. to anſwer the ſaid W. M. in a Plea of treſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>paſs: By pretext of which ſaid Writ, the ſaid E. L. the thirteenth day of <hi>July,</hi> in
<pb n="78" facs="tcp:170677:44"/> the year, &amp;c. aboveſaid at <hi>Weſtminſter,</hi> then and there, being under-Sheriff, of the ſaid A. B. then Sheriff of the ſaid County of <hi>Berks,</hi> for and in the name of the ſaid A. B. Sheriff of the ſaid Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty of B. did make two ſeveral Warrants againſt the ſaid L. G I. his wife, I. Y. and W. B. directed to the Bayliff of the hundred of <hi>Reading</hi> and <hi>Theale,</hi> to take the ſaid, &amp;c. ſo that he might have their bodies, &amp;c. to anſwer the ſaid W. M. according to the exigence of the ſaid two ſeveral Warrants: And whereas alſo in the ſame Term of the Holy Tri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nity, in the year, &amp;c. one A. P. proſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cuted one other Writ of our Lady the Queen, out of the ſame Court of, &amp;c. at, &amp;c. being to the ſaid Sheriff of the County of <hi>Berks</hi> directed; by which Writ the ſaid Sheriff was likewiſe com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>manded that he ſhould take W. G. F. M. and T. K and them ſafe keep, &amp;c. ſo that he might have their bodies before the ſaid Lady the Queen here at <hi>Weſt<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>minſter,</hi> on <hi>Wedneſday</hi> next after eight days of Saint <hi>Michael</hi> then next follow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing, to anſwer the ſaid A. P. in a Plea of treſpaſs; By pretext of which Writ
<pb n="79" facs="tcp:170677:44"/> the ſaid E. L. the ſaid thirteenth day of <hi>July,</hi> in the year, &amp;c. aboveſaid at <hi>Weſt<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>minſter,</hi> then being under-Sheriff, of the ſaid A. B. then being Sheriff of the ſaid County of B. for and in the name of the ſaid A. B. Sheriff of the ſaid County, did make two ſeveral Warrants againſt the ſaid W. G. W. F. and T. K. directed to the ſaid Bayliff of the hundred of <hi>Read<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing</hi> and <hi>Theale,</hi> in the ſaid County of B. to take the ſaid, &amp;c. ſo that he might have their bodies, &amp;c. to anſwer the ſaid A. P. according to the exigency of the ſaid ſeveral Warrants: Nevertheleſs the ſaid E. L. the Statute aforeſaid not weighing, nor regarding the penalty in the ſame Statute at <hi>Weſtminſter,</hi> the a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>foreſaid fifteenth day of <hi>February,</hi> in the year, &amp;c. did receive of the ſaid W. M. for the making of every one of the a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>foreſaid firſt four ſeveral Warrants to the ſaid Bayliff of the hundred of <hi>Reading</hi> and <hi>Theale,</hi> in the ſame County of B. directed to take the ſaid E. F. I. Y. I. G. and W. C. to anſwer to the ſaid W. M. in a Plea of treſpaſs on the ſaid <hi>Wedneſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>day,</hi> next after fifteen days of <hi>Eaſter</hi> then next following, in the ſaid Court of
<pb n="80" facs="tcp:170677:45"/> our ſaid Lady the Queen, now here at <hi>Westminſter</hi> aforeſaid, two ſhillings: and the ſaid E. L. being then the under-She<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riff of the aforeſaid A. B. of the ſaid County of <hi>Berks:</hi> By colour of his Of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fice as under-Sheriff of the ſaid County of <hi>Berks,</hi> did by way of extortion re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceive, againſt the form of the Statute a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>foreſaid, two ſhillings ſix pence: And the ſaid W. M. for making of the ſaid two ſeveral Warrants, directed to the Bayliff, &amp;c. to take the ſaid, &amp;c. to the ſaid E. L. did give two ſhillings ſix pence, &amp;c. and the ſaid E. L. by way of extor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion, under colour of his Office afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid, the ſaid two ſhillings ſix pence did to his own uſe receive, &amp;c. againſt the form of the Statute aforeſaid: Whereby an Action hath accrued to the ſaid Lady the Queen, and to the ſaid I. E. who as well, &amp;c. to have and receive of the ſaid E. L. three hundred and twenty pound; to wit, for every offence of the ſaid ſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>veral offences, forty pounds, by him according to the form of the Statute a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>foreſaid forfeited: whereupon the ſaid I. E. prayeth one moyety, according to the form of the ſaid Statute, and as
<pb n="81" facs="tcp:170677:45"/> well, &amp;c. prayeth the advice of the Court in the premiſes; and due proceſs of Law againſt the ſaid E. L. in this be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>half to be awarded, to anſwer as well to the ſaid Lady the Queen, as to the ſaid I. L. in the premiſes, &amp;c. Where<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>upon the Sheriff was commanded &amp;c. that he ſhould not omit, &amp;c. but that he attach him to anſwer, &amp;c. and now, to wit, on <hi>Friday</hi> next after the mor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>row of the holy Trinity, in the ſame Term, before the ſaid Lady the Queen at <hi>Weſtminster,</hi> came the ſaid E. L. by I. I. his Attorney: And having heard the Information aforeſaid, ſaith, That he is not thereof guilty; and of this he puts himſelf upon the Country, and G. G. Eſquire, Attorney General of the ſaid Lady the Queen, for the ſaid Lady the Queen in like manner: Therefore let a Jury thereof come before the ſaid Lady the Queen, in eight days of Saint <hi>Michael,</hi> whereſoever, &amp;c. and who, &amp;c. to recognize, &amp;c. becauſe as well, &amp;c. The ſame day is given to the ſaid G. G. who followeth, &amp;c. and to the ſaid E. L. &amp;c.</p>
               <argument>
                  <p>
                     <hi>The Sheriff in this Caſe compounded with</hi>
                     <pb n="52" facs="tcp:170677:46"/> 
                     <hi>the Informer, and ſubmitted to a Fine to the Court, as appears by the Roll.</hi> Trin. 19. Eliz. <hi>Rot.</hi> 42. inter placita <hi>Coronae. And this was for taking two ſhillings for a War<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rant; And now they will not take under two ſhillings a name for a Warrant: Sure this Statute hath lain a long time aſleep: I hope now ſome Informers will awaken the Sta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tute, and the Sheriffs and Bayliffs too.</hi>
                  </p>
               </argument>
            </div>
            <div type="indictments">
               <head>Indictments.</head>
               <div type="indictment">
                  <head>An Indictment for Buggery, with the iſſue in the Crown-Office.</head>
                  <p>M. ſſ. OTherwiſe, to wit, on <hi>Tueſday</hi> next after one moneth of <hi>Ea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſter</hi> this ſame Term, before the Lord the King at <hi>Weſtminſter,</hi> in the County of <hi>Middleſex,</hi> by the Oath of twelve Ju<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rors, it is preſented that H. S. late of <hi>London,</hi> Eſquire, God not having be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore his eyes, nor the order of nature re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>garding, but by the malice and inſtiga<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion of the Devil, being ſeduced the twelfth day of <hi>May</hi> laſt paſt, at the Pa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riſh
<pb n="83" facs="tcp:170677:46"/> of Saint <hi>Andrew</hi> in High <hi>Holborn,</hi> in the County aforeſaid, to wit, in the Manſion-houſe of one M then and there with force and arms, in and upon one R. B. a Maſculine-childe, of the age of ſixteen years, did make an aſſault: And with the ſaid R. B. then and there wic<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>kedly, diabolically, feloniouſly, and againſt nature, had carnal copulation, and him the ſaid R. then and there did carnally know; and that deteſtable and abominable ſin of Sodom (not to be na<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>med among Chriſtians) called Buggery, then and there with the ſaid R. B. wic<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>kedly, feloniouſly, diabolically, and a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gainſt nature, he did commit and per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>petrate, to the great diſpleaſure of Al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mighty God, and diſgrace of mankinde, againſt the peace of our Lord the King, His Crown and Dignity, and againſt the form of the Statute in this Caſe made and provided, &amp;c. Whereupon it was commanded the Sheriff, that he ſhould not omit, &amp;c. but that he take him, if, &amp;c. to anſwer, &amp;c. And now, to wit, on <hi>Saturday</hi> next after the morrow of the Aſcenſion of our Lord, this ſame Term, before the Lord the King at <hi>Weſt<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>minſter,</hi>
                     <pb n="84" facs="tcp:170677:47"/> came the ſaid H. S. in the cuſto<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dy of the Marſhal of the Marſhalſey of our Lord the King, before the ſaid King, to whoſe cuſtody the ſaid H. S. before, for the cauſe aforeſaid, was committed: And at the Bar here, being brought in his own perſon, in the cuſtody of the Marſhal, &amp;c. and being asked how he will acquit himſelf of the premiſes a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bove impoſed upon him, ſaith, That he is in nothing guilty thereof, and of the good and evil thereof: he puts himſelf upon the Country: Therefore let a Jury thereof come before the L. the King, here on <hi>Munday</hi> next after eight days of the Holy Trinity, next coming, and who, &amp;c. to recognize, &amp;c. becauſe, &amp;c. the ſame day is given to the ſaid H. S. in the mean time, unto the cuſtody of the ſaid Mar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſhal committed, to be ſafe kept, &amp;c. At which day before the ſaid Lord the King at <hi>Weſtminſter,</hi> came the ſaid H. S. under the Cuſtody of the ſaid Marſhal in his own perſon; And the Jurors of the Country aforeſaid, by the Sheriff of the County aforeſaid, hereunto impan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nalled, being called likewiſe came; who being elected, tryed, and ſworn
<pb n="85" facs="tcp:170677:47"/> to ſpeak the truth of the premiſes upon their Oath, do ſay, That the ſaid H. S. is guilty of the Felony and Treſpaſs a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>foreſaid, above impoſed upon him, in manner and form as he is above indi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cted: And that he hath no Goods or Chattels, Lands or Tenements, to the knowledge of the Jury aforeſaid: And hereupon he is asked if he hath any thing to ſay for himſelf wherefore the Court ſhould not proceed to judgement againſt him, and execution thereupon concerning the premiſes; who ſaith no<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thing more then what he hath already ſaid: Whereupon by the Court here the premiſes being underſtood, it is conſidered that the ſaid H. S. be hanged until, &amp;c. And the Marſhal is command<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed, that he cauſe execution to be there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>of done, on the peril, &amp;c.</p>
                  <bibl>
                     <hi>Par.</hi> 5. <hi>Jac. Rot.</hi> 3. <hi>inter placita Co<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ronae.</hi>
                  </bibl>
               </div>
               <div type="indictment">
                  <head>An Indictment for Burglary.</head>
                  <p>M. ſſ. OTherwiſe, that is to ſay, on <hi>Thurſday</hi> next after three weeks of <hi>Eaſter</hi> this ſame Term, before
<pb n="86" facs="tcp:170677:48"/> the Lady the Queen at <hi>Westminster,</hi> by the Oath of twelve Jurors it ſtands pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſented, That A. B. late of L. Yeoman, together with others, the tenth day of <hi>April,</hi> in the year, &amp;c. about the firſt hour before the middle of the night of the ſame day with force and arms, that is to ſay, with Swords, Staves, and Knives, &amp;c. the Manſion-houſe of C. D. Knight, in the County aforeſaid: one H. and E. ſervants of the ſaid C. D. Knight, then and there in the peace of God, and of our ſaid Lady the Queen, being and reſting feloniouſly and burglarily did break and enter: And ſeventy But<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tons of Gold of the weight of four ounces and a half, to the value of ele<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ven pounds; and one Jewel of Gold, with a precious Stone called an <hi>Agat,</hi> in the ſame fixed, of the value of five pounds; and fourteen pounds in mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neys, numbred of the Goods, Chat<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>t<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>ls; and moneys of one B. K. Eſquire, in the ſame houſe, then and there found feloniouſly and burglarily, did take and carry away, againſt the peace, &amp;c.</p>
                  <div type="writ">
                     <pb n="87" facs="tcp:170677:48"/>
                     <head>The Capias.</head>
                     <p>Whereupon it was commanded the Sheriff that he omit not, &amp;c. but that he take them, if, &amp;c. to anſwer, &amp;c. and now, to wit, on <hi>Wedneſday</hi> next after one moneth of <hi>Easter</hi> this ſame Term, be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore the ſaid Lady the Queen at <hi>Weſt<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>minſter,</hi> came the ſaid A. B. and the reſt under the cuſtody of N. B. and F. B. Sheriffs of the City of <hi>London,</hi> by virtue of a Writ of the Lady the Queen of <hi>Hab. Corpora,</hi> to them directed; unto whoſe cuſtody they were before for the cauſes aforeſaid, and certain other cau<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſes, committed to the Bar, here brought in their own perſons, and are com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mitted to the cuſtody of the Marſhal, &amp;c. And being ſeverally demanded how they will acquite themſelves of the premiſes above impoſed upon them, the ſaid A, B. and the reſt ſeverally ſay, That they are not thereof guilty: And of this they ſeverally put themſelves upon the Country, &amp;c.</p>
                     <p>One of the Acceſſaries confeſſeth the Indictment.</p>
                     <pb n="88" facs="tcp:170677:49"/>
                     <p> And one of them ſaith, That he can<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>not ſay but that he is guilty of being ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceſſary to the felony and burglary afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid, above impoſed upon him, in man<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ner and form as by the Indictment a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>foreſaid, it is above ſuppoſed againſt him, and the felony and burglary aforeſaid; as acceſſary thereunto he did expreſly know: And thereupon he puts himſelf upon the mercy of the Lady the Queen.</p>
                     <p>And the Jurors of the Jury aforeſaid, by the Sheriff of the County of <hi>Middle<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſex</hi> impannalled, being called likewiſe came; And being elected and ſworn to ſpeak the truth of the premiſes, ſay up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on their Oath, That the ſaid A. B. and the others, are, and every one of them is guilty in form aforeſaid, above im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poſed upon them, and that they have no Goods not Chattels, Lands nor Tene<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments, &amp;c.</p>
                  </div>
               </div>
               <div type="inquest">
                  <head>For Manſlaughter, an Enqueſt taken by the Coroner upon the view of the Body.</head>
                  <p>W. ſſ. OTherwiſe, to wit, the ſixth day of <hi>December,</hi> &amp;c. D. in the
<pb n="89" facs="tcp:170677:49"/> County aforeſaid, before I. H. one of the Coroners of the ſaid La. the Queen of the County aforeſaid, upon view of the Body of H. B. there lying dead and ſlain; by the Oath of twelve Jurors it is preſented, That the fifteenth day of <hi>December,</hi> in the year aboveſaid, at D. aforeſaid, in the County aforeſaid, it ſo happened, that I. W. late of the Pariſh of St. L. &amp;c. together with one H. M. H. D. R. S. H. W. and divers other perſons, in the houſe of one E. C. Inholder, then and there alſo being: And the ſaid H. B. unto the ſaid I. W. unknown, in the ſame houſe alſo then being, and the ſaid I. W. then and there having two little Guns in a caſe, called a caſe of Daggs; one whereof was loaden with Powder and Lead, to the ſaid I. W. likewiſe un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>known: And the ſaid H. B. did then and there deſire the ſaid I. W. to ſhew unto him the ſaid H. B. one of the Daggs aforeſaid, which the ſaid I. W. at the ſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rious requeſt of the ſaid H. B. did then and there draw forth of the caſe afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid, one of the Daggs aforeſaid, and did then and there deliver the ſame un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>to the ſaid H. B. which being ſeen by
<pb n="90" facs="tcp:170677:50"/> the ſaid H. B. he did unto the ſaid I. W. then and there again redeliver; which ſaid Gun, called a Dagg aforeſaid, the ſaid I. W. did put again into the caſe a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>foreſaid, and immediately afterwards the ſaid H. B. did again deſire the ſaid I. W. to ſhew him the Gun aforeſaid, and how he might diſcharge the ſame: And the ſaid I. W. then and there at the further requeſt of the ſaid H. B. did a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gain draw forth the Gun aforeſaid, out of the caſe aforeſaid, and asked the ſaid I. W. then and there being preſent for the Key of the Dagg aforeſaid, and whether both the ſaid caſe of Daggs were charged, or not: which ſaid H. B. then and there did anſwer the ſaid I. W. that both the ſaid Daggs were charged; and the ſaid I. W. then and there ſaid to the ſaid H. B. Art thou certain here<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>of? And the ſaid H. B. then and there again anſwered, that they were both charged, and then and there delivered the Key of the Dagg aforeſaid, unto the ſaid I. W. which ſaid I. W. the Lock of the ſaid Dagg did then and there winde up and extend; and then delivered the Dagg aforeſaid unto the ſaid H. B. ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cording
<pb n="91" facs="tcp:170677:50"/> to his requeſt aforeſaid; and without any evil felonious minde or malice forethought by the ſaid I. W. againſt the ſaid H. B. had; the Dagg a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>foreſaid ſuddenly, and by misfortune, then and there againſt the ſaid H. B. up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on the forepart of his head, with the Lead aforeſaid ſo loaden, did diſcharge it ſelf, giving to the ſaid H. then and there one mortal wound, of the depth of four fingers, and the breadth of one finger; of which ſaid deadly wound the ſaid H. B. then and there did in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtantly die: And the Jurors aforeſaid upon their Oath aforeſaid, do ſay, That the ſaid I. W. the ſaid fifteenth day of <hi>December,</hi> in the year, &amp;c. aboveſaid at D. aforeſaid, in the County aforeſaid, the ſaid H. B. in manner and form afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid, caſually and by misfortune, did kill and murther, and not otherwiſe, nor in any other manner: And further the ſaid Jurors do ſay upon their Oath aforeſaid, that the ſaid I. W. at the time of the death of the ſaid H. B. had no Goods, nor Chattels, Lands, Tene<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments to their knowledge; And the Ju<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rors aforeſaid, do appraiſe the ſaid Gun,
<pb n="92" facs="tcp:170677:51"/> called a Dagg, to ſix ſhillings and eight pence, which remains in the cuſtody of the Pariſh of D. &amp;c. <hi>inter placita Co<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ronae.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="indictment">
                  <head>
                     <hi>For Manſlaughter</hi> ſe defendendo.</head>
                  <p>K. ſſ. OTherwiſe, That is to ſay, the fourth day of <hi>October,</hi> in the year of the Raign of, &amp;c. at S. in the County aforeſaid, before I. F. Gent. one of the Coroners of our ſaid Lord the King, of the County aforeſaid, upon view of the Body of T. H. there lying dead, who was the ſervant of G. F. of M. in the County aforeſaid, Eſquire, by the Oath of twelve Jurors it ſtands preſent<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed, That the ſaid T. H. the twenty ninth day of <hi>September,</hi> in the year, &amp;c. about two of the clock in the afternoon of the ſame day, with force and arms, &amp;c. That is to ſay, with a Sword, and with a Dag<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ger, of the value of five ſhillings, which the ſaid T. H. in his hands, then and there had, and held, at S. aforeſaid, in a common foot-way, there leading be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tween S. aforeſaid, and M. towards S. in the County aforeſaid, in a certain place
<pb n="93" facs="tcp:170677:51"/> there called B. in and upon one I. H. of T. in the County aforeſaid, Yeoman, in the peace of God and of our ſaid Lord the King, then and there being, and towards M aforeſaid, then and there going; of his wicked malice forethought, did make an aſſault, and him the ſaid I. then and there with the Sword afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid, did wound, againſt the peace, &amp;c. Whereupon the ſaid I. H. (that he might keep the peace of God, and of our ſaid Lord the King, and obſerve the Laws of this Land, in this behalf provided) having in his hands for his defence, one Sword and one Dagger, of the price of five ſhillings, and himſelf then and there defending: and for the ſafeguard of his life with his Sword and Dagger aforeſaid, the furious blows and ſtrike<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ings of the ſaid I. H. from the body of him the ſaid I. H. defending and bear<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing off, and him the ſaid T. in no wiſe at all ſtriking again, but from him the ſaid T. H. continually backwards from the common foot-way aforeſaid, then and there did fly; And the ſaid T. H. the fear of God then and there not ha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ving before his eyes, but being ſeduced
<pb n="94" facs="tcp:170677:52"/> by the inſtigation, wrath, and malice of the Devil, and the ſaid I. H. to kill and murther intending, him the ſaid I. H. did then and there ſeriouſly follow, un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>til the ſaid I. by flying backwards, came to a certain corner againſt a certain hedge in the ſaid place, called B. neer the common foot-way aforeſaid, then and there being; And becauſe the ſaid I. H. for the height of the ſaid hedge, then and there being and growing could not any other ways eſcape without dan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ger of ſudden death: the ſaid I. H. then and there with his Sword and Dagger aforeſaid, in defending himſelf and for the ſafegard of his life, and of inevitable neceſſity, with his Sword aforeſaid, did ſtretch a blow towards the ſaid T. H. And him the ſaid T. by the blow afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid, with the Sword aforeſaid, upon his left arm; and from his left arm aforeſaid, ſliding down upon the belly alſo of the ſaid T. with his Sword aforeſaid, then and there did ſmite: and two ſeveral wounds, to wit, one wound upon his left arm aforeſaid, of the length of three fingers, and in breadth and depth, half a finger: and one other wound upon
<pb n="95" facs="tcp:170677:52"/> the belly of the ſaid T. half a finger broad, one finger long, and two fin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gers deep, then and there to him did give, of which ſaid wounds the ſaid T. H. from the aforeſaid hour of two a clock in the after noon of the ſame day, &amp;c. until ſix a clock in the afternoon of the thirtieth day of <hi>September</hi> aforeſaid, at S. aforeſaid, did languiſh<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> in which hour being the ſixth hour after noon of the ſaid thirtieth day of <hi>Septem.</hi> aforeſaid, in the year, &amp;c. the ſaid T. H. at S. afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid, died: And the ſaid Jurors do ſay upon their Oaths, That the ſaid I. H. the day, hour, year, and place above<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid, the ſaid T. H. with his Sword a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>boveſaid, and by the blow aforeſaid in his own defenſe, and for the ſafety of his life, and out of inevitable neceſſity, did kill: and that ſo and no otherwiſe the ſaid T. came to his death: And al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſo the Jurors aforeſaid ſay upon their Oath, That the ſaid I. H. the day and year aboveſaid, had no Goods, nor Chattels, &amp;c.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="indictment">
                  <pb n="96" facs="tcp:170677:53"/>
                  <head>For Murther upon view of the Body.</head>
                  <p>K. ſſ. OTherwiſe, to wit, the firſt day of <hi>May,</hi> in the year, &amp;c. by a certain Inquiſition indented, taken at W. in the County aforeſaid, before E. H. one of the Coroners of our ſaid Lord the King, of the County aforeſaid, upon view of the Body of I. H. late of W. aforeſaid, Husbandman, lying dead and ſlain, then and there at W. afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid, by the Oath of twelve Jurors, good and lawful men of W. aforeſaid, and three other Villages to the ſaid Vil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lage of W. aforeſaid next adjacent, as the manner and cuſtom is, who being ſworn and charged to inquire how, in what manner, and when the ſaid I. H. came to his death, upon their Oath a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>foreſaid, ſay, That on <hi>Saturday,</hi> to wit, the twenty fifth day of, &amp;c. between the hours of nine and eleven before noon, of the ſame day, the ſaid I. H. being at W. aforeſaid in the Kings high-way, leading from W. aforeſaid towards D. in the County aforeſaid, in the peace of God and of our ſaid Lord the King, one
<pb n="97" facs="tcp:170677:53"/> V. G. late of W. aforeſaid Gentleman, into the ſaid Kings high-way, then and there came: And the ſaid V. G. not having the fear of God before his eyes, but the malice and inſtigation of the Devil him ſeducing and thereunto moving, then and there, to wit, the ſaid twenty fifth day of <hi>April,</hi> in the year aboveſaid, with force and arms, purſu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing the ſaid I. H. with a certain Sword feloniouſly drawn, as a felon of our ſaid Lord the King, voluntarily, and of his malice forethought, did make an aſſault, in and upon the aforeſaid J. H. and the aforeſaid V. G. with a Sword aforeſaid of Iron and Steel, of the value of twelve pence, which the ſaid V. G. in his right hand then and there had and held drawn<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> feloniouſly; and of his malice aforeſaid, the ſaid J. H. then and there, did ſmite and wound, and gave to the ſaid J. H. then and there felo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>niouſly, and of his malice fore-thought, with the Sword aforeſaid, one deadly wound, in and upon the right part of his right thigh, of the length of three fingers, and of the depth of two fingers and a half: of which ſaid deadly wound,
<pb n="98" facs="tcp:170677:54"/> in the form aforeſaid given, the ſaid J. H. from the aforeſaid 25 day of <hi>April,</hi> in the yeer aforeſaid, until the 30 day of the ſaid month of <hi>April,</hi> at W. afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid, in the County aforeſaid, did lan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>guiſh, and live languiſhing: on which ſaid 30 day of <hi>April,</hi> in the yeer, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> aboveſaid, the ſaid J. H. at W. aforeſaid, in the County of K. aforeſaid, of the mortal wound aforeſaid, died; and ſo the Jurors aforeſaid, upon their Oath aforeſaid, do ſay that the ſaid V. G. late of W. aforeſaid, Gent. the ſaid 30 day of <hi>April,</hi> in the yeer, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> aboveſaid, at W. aforeſaid, in the County aforeſaid, the aforeſaid J. H. in manner and form aforeſaid, of his malice forethought, feloniouſly and voluntarily, did kill and murder, againſt the peace, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> And fur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thermore the ſaid Jurors do ſay upon their Oath aforeſaid, that the ſaid V. G. after the felony and murder aforeſaid, by the ſaid V. in manner and form afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid done and committed, then and there did flie away, and withdrew him<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelf to places to the Jurors aforeſaid un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>known; and what Goods and Chat<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tels, Lands or Tenements, he had at
<pb n="99" facs="tcp:170677:54"/> the time of the Felony and Murder a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>foreſaid, by him in the manner and form aforeſaid done and committed, or now hath, the Jurors are altogether ignorant. In witneſs whereof, as well the ſaid Co<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ronor as the Jurors aforeſaid, have to this Inquiſition indented, interchange<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ably put their Seals: dated the day and yeer aboveſaid. Which ſaid Indict<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment the ſaid Lord the King for certain cauſes now afterwards hath cauſed to come before him, to be determined, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="writ">
                  <head>
                     <hi>The</hi> Capias <hi>in Murder.</hi>
                  </head>
                  <p>WHereby it was commanded the Sheriff, that he ſhould not omit, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> but that he take him, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> to an<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſwer, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="presentment">
                  <pb n="100" facs="tcp:170677:55"/>
                  <head>A Preſentment for a Nuſance for not repairing of the High-way.</head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Middl.</hi> ſſ. OTherwiſe, that is to ſay, in the Term of <hi>Easter,</hi> in the yeer, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> before the Lord the King at <hi>Weſtminſter,</hi> in the County a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>foreſaid by the Oath of twelve, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> it ſtands preſented, that part of the King's High-way, in the Pariſh of S. in the County aforeſaid, containing in length four Rod, &amp; in breadth two Rod, the firſt day of M. in the year, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> was, and ſtill is, very hurtful and decayed for defect of Reparations, and amend<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing of the ſame; ſo that the liege Peo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ple of our Lord the King, labouring to paſs through the Village aforeſaid, cannot travel without danger of death, to the great and common annoyance of all the Subjects and Liege-Peo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ple of our ſaid Lord the King, through that way labouring and travelling: and that R. B. of S. aforeſaid, ought to a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mend
<pb n="101" facs="tcp:170677:55"/> and repair the aforeſaid way, when, and ſo often, as need ſhall re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quire, by reaſon of the term of his Lands and Tenements there neer adja<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cent, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
                  </p>
                  <p>Therefore it is commanded the Sheriff, that he omit not, but that he cauſe him to come to anſwer, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="indictment">
                  <head>An Indictment for Rape.</head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>S.</hi> ſſ. OTherwiſe, to wit, on <hi>Thurſday</hi> next after the week of <hi>Eaſter,</hi> in the yeer, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> at J. in the County aforeſaid, in a general Seſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſion of the Peace there held, before H. P. and M. B. Knights, and others their Fellows, Juſtices, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> by the Oath of twelve Jurors it ſtands preſented, that T. M. late of G. in the County a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>foreſaid, Yeoman, the 21 day of <hi>March,</hi> in the yeer <hi>&amp;c.</hi> by force and arms, at H. in the County aforeſaid, in and upon J. W. the Daughter of one G. W. then, and there, in the peace of God, and of our ſaid Lord the King, being, did make
<pb n="102" facs="tcp:170677:56"/> an aſſault, and her, the ſaid J. did beat, wound, and evil entreat: and the afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid J. then and there violently and a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gainſt her will, did feloniouſly raviſh, and carnally know, againſt the form of the Statute in this caſe made and provided, and againſt the Peace, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="indictment">
                  <head>An Indictment for ſtarving an Apprentice.</head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Middl.</hi> ſſ. THe Jurors for the Lord the King, upon their Oath do preſent, That W. T. late of, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> the 23 day of <hi>March,</hi> in the yeer, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> at the Pariſh aforeſaid, in the County a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>foreſaid, did retain and receive into his ſervice, one J. R. to ſerve the ſaid W. T. as an Apprentice, by the ſpace of eight yeers, thence next following. And fur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther, the ſaid J. R. then being found and healthy in body, with the ſaid W. T. from the aforeſaid 23 day of <hi>M.</hi> in the yeer aforeſaid, at the Pariſh aforeſaid, in the County aforeſaid, un<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>il the 4 day of <hi>November,</hi> in the yeer, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> in the ſer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vice
<pb n="103" facs="tcp:170677:56"/> and cuſtody of the ſaid W. T. as his Apprentice, did remain and continue: nevertheleſs, the ſaid W. T. God not having before his eyes; but of all Hu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>manity, and Chriſtian Charity, being to<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tally deprived, after the 23 day of <hi>M.</hi> in the yeer aforeſaid, to wit, between the 10 day of <hi>June</hi> in the yeer<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> 
                     <hi>&amp;c.</hi> and the 4 day of <hi>November,</hi> in the yeer a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>foreſaid, at the Pariſh aforeſaid, in the County aforeſaid, feloniouſly, volunta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rily, and of his malice forethought, did detain, and not allow unto his ſaid Ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>prentice, neceſſary and ſufficient food, for the ſuſtentation and preſervation of his life: by reaſon whereof, the ſaid J. R. between the aforeſaid 10 day of <hi>June,</hi> in the yeer aforeſaid, and the ſaid 4 day of <hi>November,</hi> in the yeer aforeſaid; then, and there, through hunger and want of nou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riſhment, died. And ſo the Jurors afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid, do ſay upon their Oath, That the ſaid W. T. his Apprentice aforeſaid, at the Pariſh aforeſaid, in the County a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>foreſaid, in manner and form aforeſaid, feloniouſly, voluntarily, and of his ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lice fore-thought, did kill and murder, againſt the Peace, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
            </div>
            <div type="statute">
               <pb n="104" facs="tcp:170677:57"/>
               <head>Hue and Cry.</head>
               <div type="judgment">
                  <head>Commit upon the Statute of Hue and Cry.</head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>G.</hi> ſſ. THe Inhabitants in the Hundreds of <hi>Langtree</hi> &amp; <hi>Crowthorne,</hi> in the County aforeſaid, were attached to an<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſwer as well the Lord the King, as J. B. who as well for the ſaid Lord the King as for himſelf, followeth, of a Plea, that whereas in a certain Statute in the Parliament holden at <hi>Wynton,</hi> in the thirteenth yeer of <hi>Edward</hi> the firſt, late King of <hi>England,</hi> made and provided; amongſt other things it ſtands ordained, for that be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cauſe Robberies, Murders and Thefts, do daily increaſe, and are from day to day committed, more then heretofore<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> and the Felons could not be attainted by the Oath of the Jurors, becauſe they too voluntarily ſuffered the Felons to eſcape, without puniſhment; and for the moſt part the Felons have been
<pb n="105" facs="tcp:170677:57"/> of the ſame County: or if they have been of any other Country, their Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceivers have been of the ſame Viſne, where the ſame Felonies have been committed. Wherefore, for their con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cealment and negligence, and to re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtrain the ſaid Felonies, the late Lord the King hath ordained a Penalty in this Caſe, that from henceforth, for fear of the Puniſhment, no Felons ſhould be ſpared or concealed; and hath com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>manded, That Proclamation ſhould be ſolemnly made in all Counties, Hun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dreds, Market-Towns, and all Chur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ches, and other places where ſolemn Aſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſemblies of people meet, ſo that none be excuſed by ignorance, That every Country from thence forward ſhould be ſo kept, that immediately after any Rob<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bery or Felony committed, freſh purſuit ſhould be made from Village to Village, and from Country to Country; and alſo inquiſition ſhould be made, if it be need<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ful, in every Town, by the Head-Officer of the Town; and afterwards in Hun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dreds and Franchiſes, and in the Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty, and ſometimes in three or four Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ties, in caſe when the Felonies are com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mitted
<pb n="106" facs="tcp:170677:58"/> in the Marches of any County; ſo that the Felons might be attainted: and if the Country ſhould not anſwer for the Felons, then the Penalty ſhould be, That every Country, that is to ſay, the Inhabitants dwelling in the ſaid Country where the Robbery is committed, ſhall anſwer for the Robberies done, and the Damages: ſo that the whole Hundred where the Robbery ſhall be committed, together with the Franchiſes in the Pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cincts of the ſaid Hundred, ſhall anſwer for the ſame Robbery. And if a Rob<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bery ſhall be committed in the Diviſion of two Hundreds, then both the ſaid Hundreds, together with their Fran<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chiſes, ſhall anſwer for the ſame: and the ſaid Country ſhall have no longer time then forty days after the Robbery committed, to make ſatisfaction for the ſame, or ſhould anſwer for the Bodies of the Felons, as by the ſaid Statute more plainly appears. And whereas a cer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tain Felon unto the ſaid J. unknown at T. in the Diviſions of the Hundreds a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>foreſaid, with force and Arms, in and upon the ſaid J. did make an aſſault, and three ſhillings and four pence of the
<pb n="107" facs="tcp:170677:58"/> monies of the ſaid J. in monies num<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bred, and one Gelding of the ſaid <hi>John</hi> of the price of ten pounds, and other Goods and Chattels of the price of for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty ſhillings, there lately found, feloni<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ouſly from the ſaid J. did take and carry away, againſt the peace of the now Lord the King. And the ſaid J. im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mediately after the ſaid Felony and Robbery aforeſaid, committed at C. neer the ſaid Hundreds of L. and C. did make Hue and Cry of the ſaid Rob<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bery, and there did give notice to the Inhabitants of the ſaid Town of C. of the Robbery aforeſaid. And after the ſaid Robbery was committed, and with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>in twenty dayes before the day of the ſuing forth of this Original Writ by the ſaid J. the ſaid <hi>John,</hi> before R. G. E<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſquire, then one of the Juſtices of the Lord the King, to keep the Peace in the ſaid County of G. aſſigned, within the Hundred of C. was examined upon his Corporal Oath, according to the form of the Statute in the twenty ſeventh yeer of the reign of <hi>Elizabeth,</hi> late Queen of <hi>England,</hi> made and provided: and the ſaid <hi>John,</hi> upon his Oath aforeſaid, did
<pb n="108" facs="tcp:170677:59"/> then ſay, That he knew not the party which did the Robbery aforeſaid. And after the robbery aforeſaid, 40 days are now paſt. And the ſaid Inhabitants of the Hundred aforeſaid, ſatisfaction of the robbery aforeſaid, to the ſaid <hi>John</hi> hither<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>to have not made; neither have they ta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ken the Body of the Felon &amp; Malefactor aforeſaid, nor for his Body hitherto have anſwered; but the Felon aforeſaid have permitted to eſcape, in contempt of the ſaid Lord the King, and to the great damage of the ſaid J. and againſt the form of the Statute of the thirteenth yeer of the reign of <hi>Edward</hi> the firſt a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>foreſaid, late King of <hi>England,</hi> made and provided, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> And whereupon the ſaid <hi>John,</hi> who as well, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> by H. W. his Attor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ney, complaineth, That whereas a cer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tain Malefactor, to the ſaid <hi>John</hi> un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>known, the 15 day of <hi>M.</hi> in the yeer <hi>&amp;c.</hi> with force and arms, that is to ſay, with Swords, Staves and Knives, in and upon the ſaid J. at T. aforeſaid, in the Diviſion of the Hundreds aforeſaid, did make an aſſault, and three ſhillings and four pence of the money of the ſaid J. in money numbred; and one Gelding
<pb n="109" facs="tcp:170677:59"/> of the ſaid J. of the price, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> and o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther Goods and Chattels, that is to ſay, one Bridle, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> there found, feloni<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ouſly from the ſaid <hi>John</hi> did take and carry away, againſt the peace, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> And the ſaid <hi>John</hi> immediately after the Fe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lony and Robery aforeſaid, committed at C. neer the ſaid Hundreds of L. and C. did make Hue and Cry of the Robbery aforeſaid: And notice of the Robbery a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>foreſaid to the Inhabitants of the ſaid Village, did then give: and after the ſaid Robbery committed, and within twenty days before the day of the ſu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing forth of the Original Writ aforeſaid, that is to ſay, the 26 day of <hi>Ianuary</hi> in the fourth yeer of the raign of our Lord the King, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> the aforeſaid J. before R. G. Eſquire, then one of the Juſtices aſſigned to keep the Peace, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> inhabi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ting neer the aforeſaid Hundreds of C. and L. to wit, at B. in the aforeſaid County of G. was examined upon his Corporal Oath, according to the form of the Statute aforeſaid, in the twenty ſeventh yeer of the raign of the late Queen <hi>Elizabeth</hi> aforeſaid, made and provided. And the ſaid <hi>Iohn</hi> upon his
<pb n="110" facs="tcp:170677:60"/> Oath aforeſaid, then ſaid, That he knew not the party which did the Robbery a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>foreſaid: &amp; that forty days are paſt, ſince the Robbery aforeſaid. Nevertheleſs, the Inhabitants of the Hundreds afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid, ſatisfaction for the Robbery afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid, to the ſaid <hi>Iohn</hi> have not made; neither have they taken the body of the Felon and Malefactor aforeſaid, nor for his Body hitherto have not anſwered; but the Felon and Robber aforeſaid, have permitted to eſcape, in contempt of the ſaid Lord, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> and to the great damage of the ſaid <hi>Iohn,</hi> and againſt the form of the Statute in the thirteenth yeer aforeſaid of the ſaid late King <hi>Ed<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ward</hi> the firſt, made and provided. Whereby he ſaith, That he is the worſe, and hath damage to the value of forty pounds: and thereupon he brings his ſuit, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
                  </p>
                  <p>And the Inhabitants aforeſaid, by R. S. their Attorney, come and defend the force and injury, when, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> and whatſo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ever, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> and ſay, That they are in no<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thing guilty of the Premiſes above im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poſed upon them, againſt the form of the Statute aforeſaid, as the ſaid <hi>Iohn,</hi>
                     <pb n="111" facs="tcp:170677:60"/> who, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> above complaineth againſt them; and of this, they put themſelves upon the Country: and the ſaid <hi>Iohn</hi> likewiſe. And hereupon the ſaid <hi>Iohn</hi> ſaith, That the Inhabitants in the afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid Hundreds of L. and C. aforeſaid, are the parties Defendants, againſt whom, the ſaid <hi>Iohn,</hi> who, as well, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> in form aforeſaid, above complaineth: and for that cauſe he prayeth a Writ of the ſaid Lord the King, to the Sheriff of the County aforeſaid, to be directed, to cauſe to come here, twelve, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> of the Viſne of the Hundred of B. in the Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty aforeſaid, for that becauſe the ſaid Hundred of B. is the next Hundred, in the County aforeſaid, adjacent to the a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>foreſaid Hundreds of L. and C. to try the iſſue aforeſaid, above in the form a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>foreſaid, joyned; and becauſe the In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>habitants of the Hundreds of L. and C. aforeſaid, do not this contradict, it is granted unto him, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> Therefore it is commanded the Sheriff, that he cauſe to come here from the day of the holy Tri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nity in three weeks, twelve, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> of the Viſne of the aforeſaid Hundred of B. by whom, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> and who neither, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> to re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cognize,
<pb n="112" facs="tcp:170677:61"/> 
                     <hi>&amp;c.</hi> becauſe, as well, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> at which day, the Jurors between the par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ties aforeſaid of the Plea aforeſaid, was reſpited between them here until this day, to wit, in eight dayes of St. <hi>Michael</hi> then next following unleſs the Juſtices of our Lord the King, aſſigned to take the Aſſizes in the County afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid, according to the form of the Sta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tute, on <hi>Monday</hi> the 20 day of <hi>Iuly</hi> next following, at G. in the County afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid, ſhould firſt come. And now here, at this day, came the aforeſaid J. by his Attorney aforeſaid: and the ſaid Ju<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtices of Aſſize, before whom, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> ſent here their Record in theſe words.</p>
                  <p>Afterwards, the day and yeer within contained, before C. Y. Knight, one of the Juſtices of the Lord the King, aſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſigned to hold Pleas before the ſaid Lord the King, and D. W. Knight, ano<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther of the Juſtices of the ſaid Lord the King, aſſigned to hold Pleas before the ſaid Lord the King, Juſtices of the ſaid Lord the King, aſſigned to take the Aſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſizes in the County of <hi>Glouceſter,</hi> accord<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing to the form of the Statute, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> came,
<pb n="113" facs="tcp:170677:61"/> as well the within named J. B. as the within written Inhabitants of the Hun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dreds of L. and C. in their proper per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons: and the Jurors of the Country within mentioned, impanalled, and cal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>led ſome of them, that is to ſay, N. F. of L. <hi>&amp;c. (ſo naming all the Jurors that appeared)</hi> came, and are ſworn upon that Jury. And becauſe the reſt of the Jurors of that Jury did not appear; therefore, <hi>(tales de circumſtantibus,)</hi> &amp;c. who being called, and ſworn to ſpeak the Truth of the matter within contain<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed; ſay upon their Oaths, That the ſaid Inhabitants of L. and C. are guilty of the Premiſes within impoſed upon them againſt the form of the Statute within written, as the ſaid J. B. hath within complained againſt them: and they do aſſeſs Damages of the ſaid J. by the occaſion within written, beſides his Coſts and Charges by him about his Suit in this behalf expended, to ten pounds, and ten ſhillings; and for his Coſts and Charges to ſix pence. Therefore it is conſidered, that the ſaid <hi>Iohn</hi> ſhall recover againſt the a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>foreſaid Inhabitants, in the Hun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dreds
<pb n="114" facs="tcp:170677:62"/> aforeſaid, his Damages afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid, to ten pounds ten ſhillings and ſix pence, by the Jurors afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid, in the form aforeſaid, aſſeſſed: and alſo nine pounds nine ſhillings and ſix pence, to the ſaid J. who, as well, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> at his requeſt for his Coſts and Charges aforeſaid, by the Court here of Increaſe, adjudged. Which Damages in the whole, do a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mount to twenty pound, and the afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid Inhabitants in mercy, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <pb n="115" facs="tcp:170677:62"/>
                  <head>Commit upon the Statute of Hue and Cry for a Robbery committed upon a Servant.</head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>E.</hi> ſſ. THe Inhabitants in the Hun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dred of B. in the County a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>foreſaid, were attached to anſwer as well unto the Lord the King, as G. R. Eſquire, of a Plea, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
                  </p>
                  <p>And whereupon the ſaid G. who as well, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> by C. N. his Attorney, com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>plaineth, That whereas certain Rob<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bers, that is to ſay, ſix men unto the ſaid G. unknown, the 10 day of N. in the yeer, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> at N. aforeſaid, in a place cal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>led, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> within the aforeſaid Hundred of B. with force and arms, that is to ſay, with Swords, Staves, Daggers and Knives, in and upon the aforeſaid H. P. Servant of the ſaid G. did make an aſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſault, and twenty and five pounds, in monies, numbered of the monies of the ſaid G. and one Gelding of the price of ten pounds of the Goods and Chat<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tels
<pb n="116" facs="tcp:170677:63"/> of the ſaid G. in the cuſtody of the ſaid H. P. then and there found, feloniouſly from the ſaid H. P. did ſpoil, rob, take, and carry away, againſt the Peace of, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> And the aforeſaid H. P. immediately after the Felony and Robbery aforeſaid, com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mitted at the aforeſaid Town of T. within the Hundred aforeſaid, which ſaid Town of T. is, and was a Town nigh the place aforeſaid, called the, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> where the ſaid Robbery afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid was committed, did make Hue and Cry of the Robbery aforeſaid; and then, and there did give notice to the ſaid Inhabitants of the ſaid Town of T. of the Robbery afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid. And after the ſaid Robbery done and committed; and within twenty days next before the bring<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ing of this Original VVrit of the ſaid G. that is to ſay, <hi>(tali Die &amp; Anno)</hi> at E. in the County afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid, the ſaid H<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> P. before J. G. then one of the Juſtices, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> was examined upon his Oath, according to the form of the Statute aforeſaid, made at <hi>Westminster</hi> in the County of
<pb n="117" facs="tcp:170677:63"/> 
                     <hi>Middleſex,</hi> in the twenty ſeventh yeer of the Reign of the late Queen <hi>Elizabeth,</hi> made and provided: And the ſaid H. upon his Oath aforeſaid, then did ſay, That he did not know the Parties which committed the Robbery aforeſaid, nor any one of them. And after the ſaid Rob<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bery was committed, ſo, as afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid, to wit, on the day of the ſu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing out of the ſaid G. that is to ſay, the thirteenth day of <hi>May,</hi> in the yeer, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> forty days are expired. Nevertheleſs, the ſaid Inhabitants within the Hundred of B. afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid, ſatisfaction for the Robbery a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>foreſaid, to the ſaid G. hitherto have not made; nor the Bodies of the Felons and Robbers aforeſaid, nor the Body of any one of them have not taken; nor for the Bodies of them, nor for the Body of any one of them, have not anſwered; but the Robbers and Felons aforeſaid, have permitted to eſcape, in contempt of the ſaid Lord the King, and to the great Da<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mage of the ſaid G. and againſt the form of the Statute aforeſaid:
<pb n="118" facs="tcp:170677:64"/> VVhereupon he ſaith, That he is the worſe, and hath Damage to the value of ſixty pounds, and there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>upon he brings his Suit, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
            </div>
            <div type="legal_process">
               <head>A Return of a Writ of Error.</head>
               <argument>
                  <p>The Record and Proceſs of the Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>plaint, whereof mention is made in this Writ, in a Schedule hereunto annexed, followeth in theſe words, (that is to ſay,)</p>
               </argument>
               <floatingText xml:lang="eng" type="declaration">
                  <body>
                     <p>THe Court of Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cord <note place="margin">The Town of <hi>Wokingam</hi> in the Counties of <hi>Berks</hi> and <hi>Wilts.</hi>
                        </note> of the Keepers of the Liberty of <hi>Eng<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>land,</hi> by Authority of Parliament, there holden at the Town of <hi>Wokingham</hi> aforeſaid, the twentieth day of <hi>June,</hi> in the yeer of our Lord God, One Thouſand, Six Hundred, Fifty and One; by vertue of a Char<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter
<pb n="119" facs="tcp:170677:64"/> of our Soveraign Lord <hi>James,</hi> of <hi>England,</hi> late King thereof, made, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> before T. G. Gent. Alderman of the ſaid Town, J. H. Eſquire, Recorder or Under-Steward of the ſaid Town, A. B. Gent. J. S. Gent. and E. V. Gent. Ca<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pital Burgeſſes of the ſaid Town. At this Court, came R. S. in his proper per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon, and complaineth againſt R. M. Ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ecutor of F. H. deceaſed, in a Plea of Treſpaſs on the Caſe, and did finde Pledges to proſecute the Plaint afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid, (that is to ſay,) J. D. and R. R. upon which the ſaid R. S. demanded Proceſs of the Court to be made againſt the aforeſaid R. M. therefore Command was given unto R. P. Sergeant at Mace, and Miniſter of the ſaid Court, That he arreſt the aforeſaid R. M. Executor of the ſaid F. H. deceaſed, and him ſafe keep, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> and that he have his Body here before the Alderman and Burgeſſes a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>foreſaid, at the next Court there held, (that is to ſay,) on <hi>Friday</hi> the three and twentieth day of <hi>June</hi> next, to anſwer to the ſaid R. S. of the Plea aforeſaid: and the ſame day is given there, unto the ſaid R. S. <hi>&amp;c.</hi> At which day, here
<pb n="120" facs="tcp:170677:65"/> at the ſame Court of the ſaid Keepers, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> at <hi>Wokingham</hi> aforeſaid, before T. G. Gent. Alderman; J. H. Eſquire, Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>corder; R. B. A. B. and J. S. Gent. Capital Burgeſſes there in the Guild-hall there held came as well the aforeſaid R. S. by G. H. his Attorney, as the aforeſaid R. M. in his proper perſon, and the afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid R. P. Sergeant at Mace, and Mini<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſter of the Court aforeſaid, did return, that he did take the aforeſaid R. M. whoſe Body he hath here to anſwer the aforeſaid R. S. of the Plaint aforeſaid, as he was commanded: and at the ſame Court, the aforeſaid R. S. by the aforeſaid G. H. his Attorney, did deſire a day to declare, until the next Court, to be hol<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>den before the ſaid Alderman and Bur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>geſſes, that is to ſay, <hi>Friday</hi> the fourth of <hi>July</hi> next following; and it was granted him: and at the next Court of the Keepers, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> before the ſaid Al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>derman and Burgeſſes held, the ſaid R. S. by <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>he ſaid G. H. his Attorney, complain<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>eth againſt the aforeſaid R. M. of the a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>foreſaid Plea, in theſe words: <hi>ſſ.</hi> The Town of <hi>Wokingham<g ref="char:punc">▪</g>
                        </hi> in the Counties of <hi>Berks</hi> and <hi>Wilts,</hi> R. S. complaineth againſt
<pb n="121" facs="tcp:170677:65"/> R. M. Executor of the laſt Will and Te<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtament of F. H. late of the Pariſh of <hi>Wokingham</hi> aforeſaid, deceaſed; in a Plea of Treſpaſs, upon the Caſe. And there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>upon the ſaid R. S. by G. H. his Attor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ney, doth ſay, That whereas the ſaid R. S. the nine and twentieth day of <hi>Sep<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tember,</hi> in the yeer of our Lord God, One Thouſand Six Hundred Forty Se<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ven, at the ſpecial Inſtance and Requeſt of the ſaid F. H. did ſell and deliver unto the ſaid F. H. at the then dwelling houſe of the ſaid J. H. in <hi>Wokingham</hi> aforeſaid, one Load of Straw; the ſaid F. in conſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>deration thereof, then and there did aſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſume, and to the ſaid R. S. did faithfully promiſe, that the ſaid F. H. would well and truely pay unto the ſaid R. S. ſo much mony as the ſaid Load of Straw, and the carriage thereof, would be reaſonably worth<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> when he ſhould be thereunto re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quired: and he, the ſaid R. Sin truth ſaith, That the ſaid Load of Straw and the car<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riage thereof, was well worth ten ſhil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ings of lawful money of <hi>England:</hi> and afterwards, the ſaid F. H died, and did not pay the ſaid ten ſhillings, nor any penny thereof, being thereunto in his
<pb n="122" facs="tcp:170677:66"/> life-time often re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quired <note n="*" place="margin">Here the Decla<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ration ſhould have ended, if it had been agreeable to the Plaint: to this part the Defendant pleaded the Sta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tute of Limitati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons, and proved the Straw carried two ſeven yeers be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore H<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                              <desc>•</desc>
                           </gap>s. death, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
                        </note>. After whoſe death, there was a certain Communica<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion had between the ſaid R. M. and one T. S. (that is to ſay,) the firſt day of <hi>A<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pril,</hi> in the yeer of our Lord God, One Thouſand Six Hun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dred Fifty and One, concerning the ſaid Load of Straw, and the carriage thereof, as aforeſaid; and the ſaid R. M. the ſaid firſt day of <hi>April,</hi> in the yeer of our Lord God, One Thou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſand Six Hundred Fifty and One, at <hi>Wokingham</hi> aforeſaid, within the Juriſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>diction of this Court, being Executor as aforeſaid, then and there did <note n="*" place="margin">This Aſſumption ſhould have been laid by it ſelf, and not declare againſt an Executor, and bring in an Aſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſumpſit of the De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fendant both in one Declaration; yet an Ho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſt Jury, and a Learned Judge, gave Verdict and Judgement both, for the Plaintiff.</note> aſſume, and faithfully promiſe to pay unto the ſaid R. S. for the ſaid Load of Str<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>w, and carri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>age
<pb n="123" facs="tcp:170677:66"/> thereof, ſo much mony as the Load of ſtraw and carriage ſhould be reaſonably worth, when he ſhould be thereunto re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quired, if he, the ſaid R. S. would ſay, upon his word, That he was not paid formerly for the ſaid Load of Staw and carriage thereof: and the ſaid R. S. in fact ſaith, That he was not paid for the ſaid Load of Straw and carriage thereof, the ſame being worth ten ſhillings, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid: yet for all that the ſaid R. M. his Promiſe and Aſſumption aforeſaid lit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tle regarding; but thinking, and frau<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dulently intending, the ſaid R. S. in this part craftily and ſubtilly to deceive and defraud; the ſaid ten ſhillings, nor any part thereof, unto the ſaid R. S. although he hath been often thereunto required, hath not hitherto paid, nor the ſaid R. S. any way contented for the ſame; but the ſame ten ſhillings hath refuſed to pay, and yet doth refuſe: whereupon the ſaid R. S. ſaith, That he is damnified twenty ſhillings; and thereupon he brings his Suit</p>
                     <closer>
                        <signed>J. A.</signed>
                     </closer>
                  </body>
               </floatingText>
               <div type="section">
                  <pb n="124" facs="tcp:170677:67"/>
                  <head>Pledges to proſecute</head>
                  <p>And the ſaid R. M. by J. A. his Attorney, did deſire Licence of Im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>parlance, and it was granted unto him; and upon this, a day thereby was given to the aforeſaid parties, until the next Court, to be held before the ſaid Alder<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>man and Burgeſſes, (that is to ſay,) <hi>Fri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>day</hi> the eleventh day of <hi>Iuly</hi> next follow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing, (that is to ſay,) to the aforeſaid R. M. to plead, and then to anſwer, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> at which next Court of the ſaid Keepers, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> truely here before the Alderman and Burgeſſes held, the ſaid R. M. further deſired Licenſe of Imparlance, and it was granted him: and upon this, a day was thereby given unto the afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid parties, until the next Court, to be holden before the ſaid Alderman and Burgeſſes, (that is to ſay,) <hi>Friday</hi> the eighteenth day of <hi>Iuly</hi> next following, (that is to ſay,) to the ſaid R. M. to im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>parle, and then to anſwer, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> truely: at which next Court of the ſaid Keepers, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> here before the ſaid Alderman and Burgeſſes to be held, (to wit) the a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>foreſaid
<pb n="125" facs="tcp:170677:67"/> eighteenth day of <hi>Iuly,</hi> came as well the aforeſaid R. S. as the afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid R. M. by their Attorneys aforeſaid, and the aforeſaid R. M. by J. A. his At<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>torney, came and defended the wrong and injury, when, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> and ſaith, That he, the ſaid R. M. made no ſuch Promiſe as the Plaintiff hath alledged againſt him; and of this, he putteth himſelf up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on his Country; and the ſaid R. like<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wiſe: therefore by the ſame Court of the ſaid Keepers, on <hi>Friday</hi> the ſaid eigh<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>teenth day of <hi>Iuly,</hi> it was commanded to R. P. Sergeant at Mace, and Miniſter of the Court aforeſaid, within the Town aforeſaid, that he ſhould cauſe to come at the next Court of the ſaid Keepers, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> here, upon <hi>Friday,</hi> to wit, the five and twentieth day of <hi>Iuly</hi> next follow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing, before the Alderman and Burgeſſes aforeſaid, to be held, twelve free and lawful men of the Town, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> by whom, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> &amp; who neither, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> to recogniſe, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> for that as well, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> &amp; at the ſame Court of the Keepers, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> on <hi>Friday</hi> the five and twentieth day of <hi>Iuly</hi> aforeſaid, the ſaid R. P. returned his Precept of his, cau<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſing to come the Jurors aforeſaid; and
<pb n="126" facs="tcp:170677:68"/> the Jurors aforeſaid called, came not: therefore it was commanded to the ſaid R. P. Sergeant at Mace, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> That at the next Court of the ſaid Keepers, <hi>&amp;c. Fri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>day</hi> the firſt of <hi>Auguſt,</hi> then next follow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing, before the ſaid Alderman and Bur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>geſſes to be held, he ſhould have the bo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dies of E. W. W. A. T. H<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> elder, J. G. J. C. R. S. Cordwainer, F. W. E. M. B. A. J. B. T. S. and J. T. to make a certain Ju<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry of the County, between the ſaid R. S. and the ſaid R. M. in the Plea aforeſaid. And the ſaid R. P. returned his Precept, with the Pannel of the Jurors aforeſaid: at which next Court of the ſaid Keepers here, to wit, on <hi>Friday</hi> the eighth day of <hi>Auguſt</hi> aforeſaid, before the Alderman and Burgeſſes aforeſaid, came the ſaid parties, in their proper perſons, and the ſaid Jurors, to wit, E. W. W. A. T. H. the elder, J. G. J. C. R. S. Cordwainer, F. W. E. M. B. A. J. B. T. S. and J. T. being called, came, and at the Court were charged and ſworn in form aforeſaid, who upon their Oath ſay, in manner and form following, that is to ſay, We finde that the ſaid R. M. the Defendant
<pb n="127" facs="tcp:170677:68"/> did <note n="*" place="margin">A malicious <hi>Knave</hi> the Proſecutor or Promoter of the Cauſe did ſwear ſo indeed; but, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
                     </note> promiſe unto the ſaid R. S. the Plaintiff, ſince the death of the ſaid F. H. the Teſtator, to pay the Load of Straw; and therefore the Jurors do aſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſeſs vj <hi>d.</hi> for Damages, and Coſts of Suit ij <hi>d.</hi> therefore it was conſidered by the ſaid Court, that the ſaid R. S. ſhould have thereof Execution, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
                  </p>
                  <p>And for any other Record of any Judgement againſt the ſaid R M. as Ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ecutor of the ſaid F. H. in this Record mentioned, we have no Judgement be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore us in the Court of Record of the ſaid Keepers, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> of the ſaid Town of <hi>Wokingham</hi> aforeſaid, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> beſides this, to certifie, as by this Writ to us it is com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>manded.</p>
                  <p>The Record and Proceſs of the afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid Plaint, with all things thereunto belonging, before the ſaid Keepers, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> whereſoever, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> at the day within ſpe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cified, we have ſent in a certain Record to this Writ annexed, as within it is to us commanded, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
                  </p>
                  <pb n="128" facs="tcp:170677:69"/>
                  <p> After this Writ was thus re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>turned, before it could be gotten out of their hands, in the abſence of the Defendants Attorney, another Record was certified for the Plain<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tiff; and in the Defendant's Writ of Error, R. was turned into T. and S. into K. <hi>&amp;c.</hi> That is in plain Engliſh, T. S. the Proſecutor, and Son of the Plaintiff, was then, and ſince hath been a ſuborning Knave; and by his Subornation and Pra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ctice, he procured in this Cauſe an Action to be brought againſt <hi>Mag<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wick,</hi> in the Court of the Honor and Caſtle of <hi>Windſor;</hi> and then, while, and afterwards, our VVrit of Error was reformed, as before, they, by the knavery or foolery, and both together, of J. H. the Steward, by a VVrit of <hi>Certiorare</hi> certified a Judgement upon the ſecond part of the Declaration of the Oath— <hi>hem</hi>
                     <pb n="129" facs="tcp:170677:69"/> 
                     <hi>vah—</hi>of <hi>T. Syms</hi> deſparately ſworn. VVhereupon, by ſurprize in Term<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>time they obtained a Judgement againſt <hi>Magwick</hi> in the Court of the Caſtle of <hi>Windſor,</hi> and I paid the money, and Caſe I record to Poſterity for a preſident of the Town of <hi>Wokingham, de quo nil bo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>num niſi ut frugam,</hi> to be practiſed by Knaves and Fools, who there grow naturally as Gold in the <hi>In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dies.</hi> And now ſince T. S. is a ſu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>borning K. and ſuborned his own Son H. S. to commit, as he did, wil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ful Perjury: which was plainly proved at the Seſſions at <hi>W.</hi> and yet, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> and ſuborned <hi>Shag-bag</hi> to ſwear againſt F. VV. at A. and out<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lawed him thereupon. I ſhall pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceed to, and conclude with a Pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſident for that wicked Crime equi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>valent to Murder, Perjury.</p>
               </div>
            </div>
            <div type="precedent">
               <pb n="130" facs="tcp:170677:70"/>
               <head>Perjury.</head>
               <bibl>
                  <hi>Stat.</hi> 5. Eliz. <hi>Cap.</hi> 5.</bibl>
               <p>
                  <hi>L.</hi> ſſ. I. S. late of H. in the County N. Gent. was ſummoned to anſwer unto A. C. who as well for the Lady the Queen, as for himſelf, in this behalf proſecutes, of a Plea, that he render un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>to the ſaid Lady the Queen, and to the ſaid A. 20 pounds, which to the ſaid La<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dy the Queen, and to the ſaid A. he ow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>eth, and unjuſtly deteineth, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> And whereupon the ſaid A. who as well for the ſaid Lady the Queen, as for himſelf, proſecutes by G. H. his Attorney, ſaith, That whereas in a certain Statute in the Parliament of our ſaid Lady the Queen, now held at <hi>Weſtminſter,</hi> in the County of <hi>Middleſex,</hi> the 12 day of <hi>January,</hi> in the fifth yeer of Her Raign: amongſt other things it ſtands enacted by the ſaid Lady the Queen, by the conſent of <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>he Lords Spiritual and Temporal, and Commons, in the ſame Parliament aſſem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bled,
<pb n="131" facs="tcp:170677:70"/> and by the Authority of the ſame; That if any perſon or perſons, after the 10 day of <hi>April,</hi> then next following, either by ſubornation, illegal procure<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment, ſiniſter perſwaſion, or any other meanes, or by their own proper Act, Conſent, or Agreement, voluntarily and corruptly ſhould commit any wilfull Perjury by his or their depoſitions, in any Court of Chancery of our ſaid Lady the Queen; Star-Chamber, White-Hall, or in any Court of our Lady the Queen, of Record, or in any Leet, view of Frank Pledge, Law day, Court of Antient de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>meaſne, Hundred Court, Court Baron; or in any Court or Courts of <hi>Stannaryes</hi> in the Counties of <hi>Devon,</hi> and <hi>Cornwal;</hi> or being examined <hi>ad perpetuam rei me<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>moriam:</hi> That then every perſon and per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons ſo offending, and being thereof lawfully convicted or atainted by the Lawes of this Land, for his or their ſaid offence, ſhall loſe and forfeit 20 pound, and ſhall ſuffer impriſonment by the ſpace of ſix months without bail or main<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>prize; and that the oath of ſuch perſon or perſons ſo offending, ſhall not from thenceforth be rendred in any Court
<pb n="132" facs="tcp:170677:71"/> of Record in <hi>England</hi> or <hi>Wales,</hi> or the Mar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ches of the ſame, until the Judgement gi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ven againſt ſuch perſon or perſons, be re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>verſed by attaint, or otherwiſe: and that upon every ſuch Averſment, the parties grieved ſhall recover his or their dama<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ges againſt all &amp; every ſuch perſon &amp; per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons, which ſhall recover the ſaid Judge<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment, ſo reverſ'd, to be giv'n againſt them, or any of them, by action or actions upon the caſe to be proſecuted againſt them, according to the courſe of the Common Law of this Land: and if it ſhall happen that the ſaid offender ſo offending, have not any Goods and Chattels, to the va<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lue of 20 pound; that then he or they ſhall be ſet upon the Pillory, in ſome Market-place, within the County, City, or Burrough, where ſuch offence ſhall be commited, by the Sheriffe or his Mi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>niſters, if it ſhall happen to be without any City, or Town-Corporate; and if it ſhall happen to be within any City, or Town-Corporate, then by the chief Officer or Officers, of ſuch City, or Town-Corporate, or by his or their Miniſters; and there to have both his Ears nailed: And from thence ſhall be
<pb n="133" facs="tcp:170677:71"/> for ever after diſabled to ſwear in any Court of Record, aforeſaid, until the Judgement ſhall be reverſed, and there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>upon<g ref="char:punc">▪</g>ſhall recover his damage, in form aforementioned; one moyety of which ſaid forfeitures ſhall be to the uſe of our Lady the Queen, her Heirs and Succeſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſors: and the other moyety to ſuch per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon or perſons who ſhall be grieved or damaged by reaſon of ſuch offence or of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fences, aforementioned, who ſhall pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſecute for the ſame, by Action of debt, Bill, Plaint, Information, or otherwiſe, in any Court of Record: wherein no wager of Law, Eſſoyne, Protection, or Injunction ſhall be allowed, as in the ſame Statute amongſt other things more plainly appeareth; Nevertheleſſe the ſaid I. the Statute aforeſaid little weighing nor the penaltie in the ſame contained any wiſe fearing, after the ſaid 10th day of <hi>April,</hi> in the yeer <hi>&amp;c.</hi> at L. <hi>&amp;c.</hi> be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore I. M. <hi>&amp;c.</hi> then being Commiſſio<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ners, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> by vertue of a certain Comiſſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on to them and others directed, out of the Court of Chancery, at <hi>Weſtminſter,</hi> in the County of <hi>Middleſex,</hi> to examine Witneſſes upon a certain Iſſue, between,
<pb n="134" facs="tcp:170677:72"/> 
                  <hi>&amp;c.</hi> And the ſaid I did then and there voluntarily and corruptly commit will<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ful Perjury againſt the form of the Sta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tute aforeſaid, that is to ſay, by ſpeaking in Engliſh theſe words following, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> whereas in truth the ſaid I. and A. did never, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> by reaſon of which falſe Perjury, the aforeſaid A. is much dama<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ged in his goods, and hath been put to expence, whereby an action hath accrued to the ſaid A who <hi>&amp;c</hi> to have and re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceive of the ſaid I. as well for the afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid <hi>&amp;c.</hi> as for himſelfe, the aforeſaid 20 pound; nevertheleſſe the aforeſaid I. although often required, the aforeſaid 20 pound to the ſaid A. who <hi>&amp;c.</hi> hath not rendred, but the ſame to the ſaid A. who <hi>&amp;c.</hi> hitherto to render hath refu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſed, and ſtill doth refuſe: whereupon the ſaid A. who <hi>&amp;c.</hi> ſaith that he is the worſe and hath damage to the value of 20 pound, and thereupon he brings his ſuit, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> and the aforeſaid I. by S. B. his Atturny commeth and defendeth the force and wrong, when <hi>&amp;c.</hi> and faith that he did not commit willful Perjury againſt the form of the Statute aforeſaid, as the aforeſaid A. who <hi>&amp;c.</hi> by his De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>claration
<pb n="135" facs="tcp:170677:72"/> aforeſaid above, doth ſuppoſe: and of this he puts himſelf upon the Country; and the aforeſaid A. who <hi>&amp;c.</hi> likewiſe.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="precedent">
               <head>Brewers.</head>
               <epigraph>
                  <bibl>Stat. <hi>Jac.</hi> Rex.</bibl>
                  <q>No Brewer ſhall ſell Beer or Ale to any Vnlicenſed Ale-Houſe, on pain of forfeiting ſix Shillings eight Pence for every Barrel.</q>
               </epigraph>
               <div type="precedent">
                  <head>Information.</head>
                  <opener>
                     <salute>To the Juſtices of the Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mon Bench.</salute>
                  </opener>
                  <p>IT is to be remembred that <hi>James Roberts,—</hi>who as well for the poor of the Pariſh of <hi>Mary Matſellon,</hi> otherwiſe <hi>White-Chap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pel,</hi> in the County aforeſaid; as for him<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelf, in this behalf, proſecutes; comes
<pb n="136" facs="tcp:170677:73"/> here into Court, the ſixteenth day of <hi>April,</hi> in the yeer of our Lord one thouſand ſix hundred fifty ſix, in his own perſon; &amp; as well for the Poor of the ſaid Pariſh, as for himſelf, he gives the Court here to underſtand and be inform<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed, That one <hi>J. W.</hi> of <hi>London,</hi> Brewer, between the firſt day of <hi>Septem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ber,</hi> laſt paſt, and the day of exhibiting this Information, at the Pariſh of <hi>Mary Matſellon,</hi> otherwiſe <hi>White-Chappel</hi> afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid, in the County aforeſaid, did ſell and utter, or cauſe to be ſold and uttered to divers perſons, whoſe names to the ſaid <hi>J. R.</hi> who, &amp;c. as yet are un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>known, two hundred Barrels of Strong-Beer, &amp; one hundred Barrels of Strong-Ale; which ſaid Beer and Ale, and e<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>very parcel thereof, was and were after<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wards, that is to ſay within the time afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid, in the Pariſh aforeſaid, within the County aforeſaid, by them ſold again as common Tiplers or Ale-Houſe-keepers; the ſaid perſons, nor any of them, hav<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing any lawful Licenſe then in force to ſell Beer and Ale; contrary to the form of a certain Statute of the third year of the Raign of King <hi>James,</hi> late King of
<pb n="113" facs="tcp:170677:73"/> 
                     <hi>England;</hi> &amp;c. in ſuch caſes made and provided. By meanes whereof he the ſaid <hi>J. W.</hi> hath forfeited to the Poor of the ſaid Pariſh, and to the ſaid <hi>J. R.</hi> who <hi>&amp;c.</hi> the ſumme of one hundred pounds of good and lawful mony of <hi>England;</hi> that is to ſay, for e<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>very Barrel of the ſaid Beer and Ale ſo by him, in manner aforeſaid, and con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>trary to the form of the Statute afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid, ſold and uttered as aforeſaid, the ſumme of ſix Shillings and eight Pence: the ſame in the whole amounting to the ſaid ſumme of one hundred pounds: Whereupon the ſaid <hi>J. R.</hi> who, &amp;c. as well for the Poor of the ſaid Pa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riſh as for himſelf, prayes the advice of the Court in the premiſes, and that due proceſs of Law may be awarded a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gainſt him the ſaid <hi>J. W.</hi> in this behalf, and that he the ſaid <hi>J. R.</hi> who <hi>&amp;c.</hi> may have the one moiety of the forfeitures aforeſaid, and the Poor of the ſaid Pariſh may have the other moi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ety thereof according to the form of the Statute aforeſaid; and moreover, that he the ſaid <hi>J.</hi> may come here into Court to anſwer the premiſes.</p>
                  <pb n="138" facs="tcp:170677:74"/>
                  <p> 
                     <hi>M.</hi> ſſ. The like Information for the ſame, and the Poor of the Pariſh of St. <hi>Giles Cripplegate,</hi> againſt <hi>Richard Daſh<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wood,</hi> of the ſame Pariſh and County, Brewer.</p>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Prohibited and ſworn the day and year above written, before me</hi>
                  </p>
                  <closer>
                     <signed>
                        <list>
                           <item>
                              <hi>John Doo,</hi>
                           </item>
                           <item>and</item>
                           <item>
                              <hi>Richard Roo,</hi>
                           </item>
                           <item>Edw. Atkins.</item>
                        </list>
                     </signed> Pledges, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
                  </closer>
               </div>
            </div>
            <div type="statute">
               <pb n="139" facs="tcp:170677:74"/>
               <head>An ACT for Diſcovering, Convicting, and Repreſsing of Popiſh REC<g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>SANTS.</head>
               <opener>
                  <dateline>At the Parliament begun at Weſtminſter <date>the ſeven<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>teenth day of September, <hi>Anno.</hi> 1656.</date>
                  </dateline>
               </opener>
               <div type="precedent">
                  <head>An Information upon the ſame Act.</head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>L.</hi> ſſ. BE it Remembred, that <hi>John Saubridge<g ref="char:punc">▪</g>
                     </hi> who as well for the now Lord Protector, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> as for him<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelf in this behalf, proſecu<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>es; came here into Court the three and twentieth day of this Terme, in his own perſon; &amp; as well for the <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>aid Lord Protector, as for himſelf, gave the Court h<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>re to un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>derſtand and be informed, That where<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>as
<pb n="131" facs="tcp:170677:75"/> at the Parliament begun at <hi>Weſtminſter</hi> the ſeventeenth day of <hi>September,</hi> in the year of our Lord 1656. for the Repreſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſing, Convicting, and Diſcovering of Po<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>piſh Recuſants; it ſtands enacted by the ſame Parliament, in a certain Act at the ſame Parliament made, entituled, An Act for the Diſcovering, Convicting, and Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>preſſing of Popiſh Recuſants, made and provided: Amongſt other things in the ſame Act contained, That it ſhall not be lawful for any Subject of this Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>monwealth (other then the houſehold<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſervants that ſhall come over with any Ambaſſador or Agent) at any time to be preſent at Maſſe, at the houſe of any ſuch Ambaſſador or Agent, or any other place whatſoever, upon pain and penalty of one hundred pounds, and impriſonment by the ſpace of ſix Months; The one moyety of the ſaid forfeiture to be to the uſe of his Highneſs the Lord Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tector, and his Succeſſors; and the o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther moyety to the Informer, to be re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>covered by Action, Bill, Plaint, Suit or In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>formation in any Courr of Record; in which no Eſſoign, Protection, or Wager of Law ſhall be allowed. Nevertheleſſe
<pb n="137" facs="tcp:170677:75"/> one A. B. late of <hi>London</hi> aforeſaid Gent. the Act aforeſaid, nor the Penalties in the ſame regarding, at <hi>London,</hi> aforeſaid, that is to ſay <hi>(Tali die &amp; loco)</hi> did volun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tarily repaire unto the place and houſe aforeſaid, and then and there was pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſent, and did hear one Popiſh Maſſe ſaid or ſung, according to the manner and cuſtome of the Church of <hi>Rome;</hi> againſt the form of the ſaid late Act of Parlia<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment, in this caſe made and provided<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> by meanes whereof, he the ſaid A. B. hath forfeited to the ſaid Lord Protector, and I. S. who <hi>&amp;c.</hi> the ſumme of an hundred pounds of lawful money of <hi>England.</hi> Whereupon the ſaid I. S. as well for the ſaid Lord Protector as for himſelf, pray<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>eth the advice of the Court here in the Premiſes, and that due proceſſe of Law may be awarded againſt the ſaid A. B. in this behalf: and that he the ſaid I. S. who <hi>&amp;c.</hi> may have one moyety of the forfeiture aforeſaid: and that he, the ſaid A. B. may ſuffer impriſonment by the ſpace of ſix Months according to the the form of the Act aforeſaid: and moreover that he come here into Court to anſwer the Premiſes, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
            </div>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="publishers_advertisement">
            <pb facs="tcp:170677:76"/>
            <head>
               <hi>Theſe Books following are to be ſold at the Lamb, at the Eaſt end of St.</hi> Pauls, <hi>neer the School.</hi>
            </head>
            <p>THe Secretaries ſtudy; A Piece of Elegant Letters in Faſhi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on.</p>
            <p>The Compleat Bone-Setter.</p>
            <p>A rare Treatiſe of the Philoſo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>phers Salt: both by Dr. <hi>Turner.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Two ſober Paradoxes: By <hi>Mal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vezzi, Elementa Optica,</hi> in Oct.</p>
            <p>Mr. <hi>Wentworth's Miſcellania;</hi> a Piece of School-Divinity.</p>
            <p>There is in the Preſs, Re-Print<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing with Additions and Amend<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments, that moſt wanted Piece of Fawlconry: By Mr. <hi>Latham.</hi>
            </p>
            <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
            <pb facs="tcp:170677:76"/>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>
